import 'package:Learner/data/electrical/electricalList.dart';

class QuestionModel {
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}

List<bits> mec = [
  bits(a: Aerospace),
  bits(a: Automotive),
  bits(a: bearings),
  bits(a: biomechanics),
  bits(a: CAD),
  bits(a: Computational),
  bits(a: controlsystem),
  bits(a: fluidflow),
  bits(a: fluidmechanics),
  bits(a: fluidpowersystem),
  bits(a: heattransfer),
  bits(a: Kinematicsanddynamics),
  bits(a: machineElements),
  bits(a: machinedesign),
  bits(a: manufacturingprocess),
  bits(a: materialscience),
  bits(a: mechanics),
  bits(a: mechatronics),
  bits(a: solidmechanics),
  bits(a: thermodynamics),
];

List<QuestionModel> Aerospace = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. Which famous American aviator is known for being the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?",
      options: [
        "A. Amelia Earhart",
        "B. Chuck Yeager",
        "C. Charles Lindbergh",
        "D. Neil Armstrong"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Charles Lindbergh. Charles Lindbergh made history by completing the first solo nonstop transatlantic flight in 1927, flying from New York to Paris."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. What is the term for the speed at which an aircraft's forward motion overcomes the force of gravity and allows it to become airborne?",
      options: [
        "A. Lift-off velocity",
        "B. Stall speed",
        "C. Takeoff speed",
        "D. Groundspeed"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Takeoff speed. Takeoff speed is the speed at which an aircraft generates enough lift to become airborne, typically just before the wheels leave the ground."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. In aerospace engineering, what is the purpose of ailerons on an aircraft's wings?",
      options: [
        "A. To control pitch",
        "B. To control roll",
        "C. To control yaw",
        "D. To control thrust"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To control roll. Ailerons are control surfaces on an aircraft's wings that are used to control the rolling motion of the aircraft by varying lift on one wing compared to the other."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "4. What is the primary function of a gyroscope in aviation?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide in-flight entertainment",
        "B. To measure airspeed",
        "C. To provide stability and control reference",
        "D. To navigate using GPS"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To provide stability and control reference. Gyroscopes in aviation are used to provide a stable reference for controlling an aircraft's orientation and stability."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. Which law of motion, formulated by Sir Isaac Newton, explains the relationship between an aircraft's motion and the forces acting upon it?",
      options: [
        "A. Newton's First Law of Motion",
        "B. Newton's Second Law of Motion",
        "C. Newton's Third Law of Motion",
        "D. Newton's Law of Universal Gravitation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Newton's Third Law of Motion. Newton's Third Law of Motion states that for every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction, which is fundamental in understanding aircraft motion and control."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What is the purpose of the vertical stabilizer (fin) on an aircraft's tail?",
      options: [
        "A. To control pitch",
        "B. To control roll",
        "C. To control yaw",
        "D. To control thrust"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To control yaw. The vertical stabilizer, or fin, is responsible for controlling the yawing motion of the aircraft by providing stability and directional control."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. In supersonic flight, what term is used to describe the shock waves generated by an aircraft moving at a speed greater than the speed of sound?",
      options: [
        "A. Sonic boom",
        "B. Jetstream",
        "C. Vortex wake",
        "D. Thermals"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Sonic boom. A sonic boom is the shockwave produced by an object traveling through the air at a speed greater than the speed of sound, creating a loud noise."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. Which part of a rocket engine is responsible for expelling high-speed exhaust gases to generate thrust?",
      options: ["A. Nose cone", "B. Payload bay", "C. Rocket motor", "D. Fins"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Rocket motor. The rocket motor is the part of a rocket engine that expels high-speed exhaust gases, creating the thrust needed for propulsion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What type of engine is commonly used in most commercial jet airliners for propulsion?",
      options: [
        "A. Turbofan engine",
        "B. Turbojet engine",
        "C. Piston engine",
        "D. Ramjet engine"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Turbofan engine. Most commercial jet airliners are powered by turbofan engines, which are efficient and quiet compared to other engine types."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which organization is responsible for the coordination of air traffic control and navigation services in the United States?",
      options: [
        "A. NASA",
        "B. FAA (Federal Aviation Administration)",
        "C. NTSB (National Transportation Safety Board)",
        "D. DOT (Department of Transportation)"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. FAA (Federal Aviation Administration). The FAA is responsible for the regulation and oversight of civil aviation, including air traffic control and navigation services in the United States."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the term for the highest point an aircraft can reach in its flight path before descending?",
      options: ["A. Apogee", "B. Perigee", "C. Altitude", "D. Zenith"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Zenith. Zenith refers to the highest point in an aircraft's flight path before it begins to descend. It is also known as the aircraft's peak or summit."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. In astronautics, what is the boundary that separates the Earth's atmosphere from outer space called?",
      options: [
        "A. Stratosphere",
        "B. Thermosphere",
        "C. Mesopause",
        "D. Kármán line"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Kármán line. The Kármán line, located at an altitude of approximately 100 kilometers (62 miles), is the internationally recognized boundary that separates Earth's atmosphere from outer space."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the primary function of the International Space Station (ISS) in space exploration?",
      options: [
        "A. Space tourism",
        "B. Satellite deployment",
        "C. Scientific research and experimentation",
        "D. Lunar landings"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Scientific research and experimentation. The ISS serves as a platform for scientific research and experiments in microgravity, as well as international cooperation in space exploration."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. Which American space agency is responsible for the Apollo moon landing missions?",
      options: [
        "A. NASA",
        "B. SpaceX",
        "C. Blue Origin",
        "D. ESA (European Space Agency)"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. NASA. NASA, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, was responsible for the Apollo moon landing missions, including the historic Apollo 11 mission in 1969."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What does the acronym UAV stand for in aerospace technology?",
      options: [
        "A. Unmanned Aerial Vehicle",
        "B. Ultrafast Aviation Vehicle",
        "C. Universal Aerospace Vessel",
        "D. Unmanned Airborne Vehicle"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Unmanned Aerial Vehicle. UAV stands for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle, which refers to aircraft operated without a human pilot on board."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What concept in aerospace engineering is used to describe the bending of an aircraft's wings during flight?",
      options: [
        "A. Wing twist",
        "B. Flutter",
        "C. Wing loading",
        "D. Wing flex"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Wing flex. Wing flex is the bending or deformation of an aircraft's wings under various aerodynamic forces experienced during flight, such as turbulence and gusts."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. Which famous astronaut was the first person to set foot on the Moon during the Apollo 11 mission in 1969?",
      options: [
        "A. John Glenn",
        "B. Yuri Gagarin",
        "C. Buzz Aldrin",
        "D. Neil Armstrong"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Neil Armstrong. Neil Armstrong was the first person to set foot on the Moon during the historic Apollo 11 mission."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the term for the aircraft's ability to maintain controlled flight during a stall condition?",
      options: [
        "A. Glide ratio",
        "B. Stall speed",
        "C. Angle of attack",
        "D. Autorotation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Glide ratio. The glide ratio refers to the aircraft's ability to maintain controlled flight during a stall condition, indicating how far the aircraft can glide for a given altitude loss."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What type of propulsion system is commonly used in spacecraft to maneuver in the vacuum of space?",
      options: [
        "A. Turboprop engines",
        "B. Ion thrusters",
        "C. Ramjets",
        "D. Turbofan engines"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Ion thrusters. Ion thrusters are commonly used in spacecraft for propulsion in the vacuum of space due to their high efficiency and low fuel consumption."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. In aerodynamics, what term is used to describe the flow of air around an aircraft's wing or body when it is traveling at a high speed close to the speed of sound?",
      options: [
        "A. Subsonic flow",
        "B. Hypersonic flow",
        "C. Transonic flow",
        "D. Supersonic flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Supersonic flow. Supersonic flow occurs when an aircraft is traveling at a high speed close to or above the speed of sound, resulting in shock waves and other aerodynamic effects.")
];

List<QuestionModel> Automotive = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. Which part of an internal combustion engine is responsible for converting reciprocating motion into rotary motion?",
      options: [
        "A. Crankshaft",
        "B. Camshaft",
        "C. Piston",
        "D. Cylinder head"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Crankshaft. The crankshaft is responsible for converting the reciprocating motion of the pistons into rotary motion, which is used to drive the vehicle's wheels."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. What type of transmission is most commonly found in modern passenger vehicles?",
      options: [
        "A. Manual transmission",
        "B. Automatic transmission",
        "C. Continuously variable transmission (CVT)",
        "D. Semi-automatic transmission"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Automatic transmission. Automatic transmissions are the most common type of transmission in modern passenger vehicles because they are easier to use and offer a smoother driving experience."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "3. What is the purpose of an automotive differential?",
      options: [
        "A. To steer the vehicle",
        "B. To transfer power to the wheels",
        "C. To control the engine's RPM",
        "D. To adjust the suspension"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To transfer power to the wheels. The differential is responsible for distributing power from the engine to the wheels while allowing them to rotate at different speeds, especially during turns."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which of the following is an example of a hybrid electric vehicle (HEV)?",
      options: [
        "A. Tesla Model S",
        "B. Toyota Prius",
        "C. Ford F-150",
        "D. BMW M3"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Toyota Prius. The Toyota Prius is an example of a hybrid electric vehicle (HEV) that combines a gasoline engine with an electric motor for improved fuel efficiency."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What component in a car's suspension system is responsible for absorbing shocks and vibrations?",
      options: [
        "A. Brake caliper",
        "B. Shock absorber",
        "C. Tie rod",
        "D. Steering wheel"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Shock absorber. The shock absorber (or damper) is designed to absorb and dampen the shocks and vibrations generated by the road, providing a smoother and more comfortable ride."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. In an automotive engine, what does the term 'redline' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. The color of the engine coolant",
        "B. The highest engine speed at which it can safely operate",
        "C. The brand of engine oil used",
        "D. The engine's serial number"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. The highest engine speed at which it can safely operate. The redline is the maximum RPM (revolutions per minute) at which the engine can safely operate without causing damage."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. Which type of braking system uses hydraulic pressure to apply the brakes?",
      options: [
        "A. Mechanical brakes",
        "B. Drum brakes",
        "C. Disc brakes",
        "D. Hydraulic brakes"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Hydraulic brakes. Hydraulic brakes use hydraulic pressure to transmit force from the brake pedal to the brake calipers or drums, resulting in effective braking."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What does ABS stand for in the context of automotive safety?",
      options: [
        "A. Advanced Braking System",
        "B. Anti-Lock Braking System",
        "C. Automatic Braking System",
        "D. Active Brake System"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Anti-Lock Braking System. ABS is an abbreviation for Anti-Lock Braking System, which prevents wheel lockup during hard braking, improving control and safety."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "9. What is the primary function of an automotive radiator?",
      options: [
        "A. To cool the engine oil",
        "B. To filter impurities from the fuel",
        "C. To cool the engine by dissipating heat",
        "D. To regulate the air-fuel mixture"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To cool the engine by dissipating heat. Radiators are designed to cool the engine by dissipating heat generated during the combustion process, helping to maintain the engine's temperature within the optimal range."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. What is the purpose of a turbocharger in an automotive engine?",
      options: [
        "A. To increase fuel efficiency",
        "B. To reduce emissions",
        "C. To provide extra engine power",
        "D. To improve engine longevity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To provide extra engine power. A turbocharger is used to force more air into the engine, which results in increased power output without the need for a larger engine."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. Which part of a car's exhaust system is responsible for reducing harmful emissions?",
      options: [
        "A. Muffler",
        "B. Catalytic converter",
        "C. Tailpipe",
        "D. Exhaust manifold"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Catalytic converter. The catalytic converter is designed to reduce harmful emissions by converting them into less harmful substances before they are released into the atmosphere."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the purpose of the OBD-II (On-Board Diagnostics) system in modern vehicles?",
      options: [
        "A. To play music in the car",
        "B. To monitor engine performance",
        "C. To control the air conditioning",
        "D. To operate the navigation system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To monitor engine performance. OBD-II is used to monitor and diagnose the performance of the vehicle's engine and emissions control systems, helping with maintenance and emissions compliance."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "13. Which type of fuel is commonly used in diesel engines?",
      options: ["A. Gasoline", "B. Propane", "C. Diesel fuel", "D. Ethanol"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Diesel fuel. Diesel engines typically use diesel fuel, which is a specific type of fuel designed for compression-ignition engines."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What does the acronym CVT stand for in automotive transmission technology?",
      options: [
        "A. Constant Velocity Transmission",
        "B. Continuously Variable Transmission",
        "C. Central Valve Timing",
        "D. Controlled Viscosity Transfer"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Continuously Variable Transmission. CVT stands for Continuously Variable Transmission, which offers a continuous range of gear ratios for improved efficiency and performance."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. Which automotive safety feature is designed to inflate rapidly in the event of a collision to protect occupants?",
      options: [
        "A. Air conditioning system",
        "B. Air suspension",
        "C. Airbag",
        "D. Anti-theft system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Airbag. Airbags are designed to inflate rapidly upon collision impact, providing a cushion to protect vehicle occupants from injury."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What does AWD stand for in the context of vehicle drivetrains?",
      options: [
        "A. Advanced Wheel Drive",
        "B. All Weather Drive",
        "C. Automatic Wheel Drive",
        "D. All-Wheel Drive"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. All-Wheel Drive. AWD stands for All-Wheel Drive, which provides power to all four wheels simultaneously for improved traction and stability, especially in adverse road conditions."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the purpose of the transmission fluid in an automatic transmission?",
      options: [
        "A. To lubricate the engine",
        "B. To cool the transmission",
        "C. To power the steering system",
        "D. To engage the brakes"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To cool the transmission. Transmission fluid in an automatic transmission serves to cool and lubricate the transmission components, ensuring smooth operation and preventing overheating."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the term for the process of converting chemical energy in fuel into mechanical energy in an engine?",
      options: [
        "A. Combustion",
        "B. Compression",
        "C. Exhaustion",
        "D. Ignition"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Combustion. Combustion is the process in which chemical energy in fuel is converted into mechanical energy through the controlled burning of the fuel in the engine's cylinders."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the role of the power steering system in a vehicle?",
      options: [
        "A. To increase fuel efficiency",
        "B. To reduce engine noise",
        "C. To make steering easier for the driver",
        "D. To control the vehicle's speed"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To make steering easier for the driver. The power steering system assists the driver in turning the wheels, making it easier to steer the vehicle, especially at low speeds or when parking."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. In an electric vehicle (EV), what type of battery is commonly used for energy storage?",
      options: [
        "A. Alkaline battery",
        "B. Lead-acid battery",
        "C. Lithium-ion battery",
        "D. Nickel-cadmium battery"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Lithium-ion battery. Lithium-ion batteries are commonly used in electric vehicles (EVs) for energy storage due to their high energy density, lightweight, and long cycle life.")
];

List<QuestionModel> bearings = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. What is the primary function of a bearing in a machine?",
      options: [
        "A. To transmit power",
        "B. To provide radial support",
        "C. To create a sealing barrier",
        "D. To reduce vibrations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To provide radial support. Bearings in a machine primarily provide radial support to rotating or moving components and reduce friction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. Which type of bearing is known for its ability to support both radial and axial loads?",
      options: [
        "A. Ball bearing",
        "B. Roller bearing",
        "C. Thrust bearing",
        "D. Sleeve bearing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Roller bearing. Roller bearings are designed to support both radial and axial loads, making them versatile for various applications."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "3. What is the purpose of lubrication in a bearing?",
      options: [
        "A. To create a sealing barrier",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To reduce friction",
        "D. To change direction of rotation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To reduce friction. Lubrication in a bearing serves the primary purpose of reducing friction between moving parts."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which type of lubricant is commonly used in high-temperature applications due to its resistance to thermal breakdown?",
      options: [
        "A. Oil-based lubricant",
        "B. Grease",
        "C. Dry lubricant",
        "D. Silicone lubricant"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Oil-based lubricant. Oil-based lubricants are often used in high-temperature applications because they have good resistance to thermal breakdown."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. In a plain bearing (sleeve bearing), what material is commonly used for the bearing surface?",
      options: ["A. Steel", "B. Copper", "C. Bronze", "D. Aluminum"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Bronze. Bronze is a commonly used material for the bearing surface in plain bearings due to its excellent sliding properties."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What type of lubrication system relies on gravity to feed lubricant to the bearing components?",
      options: [
        "A. Oil mist lubrication",
        "B. Splash lubrication",
        "C. Forced lubrication",
        "D. Mist lubrication"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Splash lubrication. Splash lubrication relies on gravity to splash or feed lubricant onto the bearing components within the machine."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "7. What is the function of a thrust bearing in a machine?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide radial support",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To reduce vibrations",
        "D. To support axial loads"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To support axial loads. Thrust bearings are designed to support axial (thrust) loads, preventing movement in the axial direction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. Which lubrication method delivers a fine mist of lubricant to the bearing through an atomized spray?",
      options: [
        "A. Grease lubrication",
        "B. Oil bath lubrication",
        "C. Forced lubrication",
        "D. Mist lubrication"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Mist lubrication. Mist lubrication delivers a fine mist of lubricant to the bearing by atomizing the lubricating oil."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is the primary function of a bearing housing in a machine?",
      options: [
        "A. To reduce friction",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To provide a housing for the bearing",
        "D. To create a sealing barrier"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To provide a housing for the bearing. A bearing housing serves as a protective enclosure for the bearing, providing support and protection."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which lubrication method utilizes a solid lubricant, such as graphite, to reduce friction between bearing surfaces?",
      options: [
        "A. Oil lubrication",
        "B. Grease lubrication",
        "C. Dry lubrication",
        "D. Mist lubrication"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Dry lubrication. Dry lubrication uses a solid lubricant to reduce friction between bearing surfaces without a liquid lubricant."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the primary function of an oil seal (shaft seal) in a machine element?",
      options: [
        "A. To reduce friction",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To provide radial support",
        "D. To create a sealing barrier"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To create a sealing barrier. An oil seal, also known as a shaft seal, is designed to create a barrier to prevent the leakage of fluids, such as oil, from the machine."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. Which type of lubricant is commonly used for lubricating gears and heavily loaded bearings?",
      options: [
        "A. Oil-based lubricant",
        "B. Dry lubricant",
        "C. Silicone lubricant",
        "D. Graphite lubricant"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Oil-based lubricant. Oil-based lubricants are often used to lubricate gears and heavily loaded bearings due to their lubricating properties."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the purpose of an anti-friction bearing (rolling bearing) cage or retainer?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide radial support",
        "B. To reduce vibrations",
        "C. To prevent relative rotation",
        "D. To transmit power"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To prevent relative rotation. The cage or retainer in an anti-friction bearing holds the rolling elements in position and prevents their relative rotation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. Which type of bearing is suitable for applications where alignment between shafts is critical, such as in a cardan joint (universal joint)?",
      options: [
        "A. Needle roller bearing",
        "B. Spherical roller bearing",
        "C. Tapered roller bearing",
        "D. Thrust bearing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Spherical roller bearing. Spherical roller bearings allow for angular misalignment between shafts, making them suitable for applications like cardan joints."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What is the primary purpose of a thrust washer in a bearing assembly?",
      options: [
        "A. To create a sealing barrier",
        "B. To reduce friction",
        "C. To provide axial support",
        "D. To transmit power"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To provide axial support. Thrust washers are used to provide axial support and reduce friction in bearing assemblies subject to axial loads."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. In a plain journal bearing, what type of lubrication system is commonly used for applications with slow-moving machinery?",
      options: [
        "A. Mist lubrication",
        "B. Forced lubrication",
        "C. Oil bath lubrication",
        "D. Grease lubrication"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Oil bath lubrication. Oil bath lubrication is commonly used in plain journal bearings for slow-moving machinery where a constant supply of oil is required."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. Which type of rolling bearing is typically used for high radial load applications and can accommodate both radial and axial loads?",
      options: [
        "A. Needle roller bearing",
        "B. Spherical roller bearing",
        "C. Tapered roller bearing",
        "D. Thrust bearing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Tapered roller bearing. Tapered roller bearings are used for high radial load applications and can accommodate both radial and axial loads."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the primary function of a bearing preload in an angular contact ball bearing?",
      options: [
        "A. To reduce friction",
        "B. To create a sealing barrier",
        "C. To provide axial support",
        "D. To remove radial play"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To remove radial play. Bearing preload in an angular contact ball bearing removes any radial play or clearance to ensure precise axial positioning."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. In a machine element, what is the primary purpose of a thrust collar?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide radial support",
        "B. To reduce vibrations",
        "C. To support axial loads",
        "D. To create a sealing barrier"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To support axial loads. A thrust collar is used to provide axial support and prevent axial movement in machine elements."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. Which type of bearing is commonly used in applications where space is limited, and high radial loads need to be supported?",
      options: [
        "A. Needle roller bearing",
        "B. Spherical roller bearing",
        "C. Tapered roller bearing",
        "D. Thrust bearing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Needle roller bearing. Needle roller bearings are used in applications with limited space and high radial loads due to their compact design.")
];

List<QuestionModel> biomechanics = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. Which of the following is a fundamental concept in biomechanics that describes the study of forces and their effects on the human body?",
      options: ["A. Physiology", "B. Anatomy", "C. Kinematics", "D. Dynamics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Dynamics. Biomechanics involves the study of forces and their effects on the human body, and dynamics is a fundamental branch of biomechanics that focuses on the study of motion and the forces that cause it."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. What is the term for the study of the structure and function of the human body, including bones, muscles, and organs?",
      options: [
        "A. Physiology",
        "B. Anatomy",
        "C. Kinesiology",
        "D. Anthropology"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Anatomy. Anatomy is the branch of biology that focuses on the study of the structure and organization of the human body, including its bones, muscles, and organs."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. Which biomechanical concept refers to the study of the motion of the human body without considering the forces that cause the motion?",
      options: [
        "A. Kinematics",
        "B. Dynamics",
        "C. Kinesiology",
        "D. Anthropometry"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Kinematics. Kinematics in biomechanics involves the study of the motion of the human body, including parameters like speed, acceleration, and displacement, without considering the forces that cause the motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. In biomechanics, what is the term for the branch of science that deals with the measurement of the human body's physical properties and dimensions?",
      options: [
        "A. Physiology",
        "B. Anthropology",
        "C. Ergonomics",
        "D. Anthropometry"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Anthropometry. Anthropometry is the branch of science that focuses on the measurement of the physical properties and dimensions of the human body, such as height, weight, and limb length."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. Which of the following is an example of a joint in the human body that allows for rotational motion?",
      options: [
        "A. Hinge joint (elbow)",
        "B. Ball and socket joint (hip)",
        "C. Fixed joint (skull)",
        "D. Saddle joint (thumb)"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Ball and socket joint (hip). Ball and socket joints, like the hip joint, allow for rotational motion in multiple directions and are essential for movements such as hip flexion and rotation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. Which biomechanical concept describes the study of how external forces affect the human body's movement and stability?",
      options: [
        "A. Kinematics",
        "B. Dynamics",
        "C. Anthropometry",
        "D. Ergonomics"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Dynamics. Dynamics in biomechanics focuses on the study of how external forces affect the motion and stability of the human body, including concepts like balance and equilibrium."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the term for the study of the mechanics of human movement, including gait analysis and posture assessment?",
      options: [
        "A. Physiology",
        "B. Kinesiology",
        "C. Anthropometry",
        "D. Ergonomics"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Kinesiology. Kinesiology is the study of the mechanics of human movement, encompassing areas like gait analysis, posture assessment, and exercise science."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. In the context of biomechanics, what is the name for the application of scientific and engineering principles to improve the design of tools, equipment, and workspaces for human use?",
      options: [
        "A. Anthropology",
        "B. Anthropometry",
        "C. Ergonomics",
        "D. Kinesiology"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Ergonomics. Ergonomics involves the application of scientific and engineering principles to enhance the design of tools, equipment, and workspaces to optimize human comfort and performance."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. Which part of the human spine is responsible for supporting the head and allowing for its rotational movement?",
      options: [
        "A. Thoracic spine",
        "B. Lumbar spine",
        "C. Cervical spine",
        "D. Sacral spine"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Cervical spine. The cervical spine, located in the neck region, supports the head and enables its rotational movement, as well as flexion and extension."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. In biomechanics, what is the term for the resistance of a material to deformation, such as stretching or compression?",
      options: ["A. Tension", "B. Compression", "C. Stress", "D. Strain"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Stress. Stress in biomechanics represents the resistance of a material to deformation, which can include stretching, compression, or shearing forces."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What type of muscle contraction occurs when the muscle shortens while generating force, as in lifting a weight?",
      options: [
        "A. Isometric contraction",
        "B. Concentric contraction",
        "C. Eccentric contraction",
        "D. Static contraction"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Concentric contraction. Concentric contraction occurs when a muscle shortens while generating force, such as when lifting a weight during a bicep curl."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. Which of the following is an example of a commonly used medical imaging technique to study the biomechanics of the human body?",
      options: [
        "A. Electrocardiogram (ECG)",
        "B. Positron emission tomography (PET)",
        "C. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)",
        "D. Electroencephalogram (EEG)"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). MRI is a medical imaging technique that provides detailed images of the internal structures of the human body and is often used to study biomechanics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the term for the study of the interaction between living organisms and the mechanical aspects of their environment?",
      options: [
        "A. Kinesiology",
        "B. Ergonomics",
        "C. Biomechanics",
        "D. Anthropology"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Biomechanics. Biomechanics is the study of the mechanical aspects of living organisms, including how they interact with their environment and how they move and function."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. Which of the following is a common parameter used to measure the mechanical stress on bones and tissues in biomechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. Cardiac output",
        "B. Strain rate",
        "C. Body temperature",
        "D. Strain"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Strain. Strain is a common parameter used in biomechanics to measure the deformation or elongation of bones and tissues under mechanical stress."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What is the term for the study of the interaction between the human body and the external environment to optimize performance and prevent injury?",
      options: [
        "A. Kinesiology",
        "B. Ergonomics",
        "C. Anthropometry",
        "D. Biomechanics"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Ergonomics. Ergonomics focuses on the study of the interaction between the human body and the external environment to optimize performance, comfort, and safety while preventing injury."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. Which of the following factors contributes to the understanding of human biomechanics in sports and exercise?",
      options: ["A. Gravity", "B. Time zones", "C. Geology", "D. Astronomy"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Gravity. Gravity is a fundamental factor that influences human biomechanics in sports and exercise, affecting movements, balance, and resistance to motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. In the context of biomechanics, what is the term for the study of the motion and posture of the human body, especially during physical activities?",
      options: [
        "A. Anatomy",
        "B. Kinesiology",
        "C. Anthropometry",
        "D. Kinematics"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Kinematics. Kinematics in biomechanics involves the study of the motion and posture of the human body, particularly during physical activities and exercises."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. Which of the following is a common method used to analyze and quantify the forces acting on the human body during movements or activities?",
      options: [
        "A. Anthropometry",
        "B. Goniometry",
        "C. Electromyography (EMG)",
        "D. Holography"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Electromyography (EMG). Electromyography is a common method used in biomechanics to analyze and quantify the electrical activity of muscles, allowing researchers to assess the forces generated during movements."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. Which term in biomechanics refers to the study of how muscles produce forces and motion in the human body?",
      options: [
        "A. Myology",
        "B. Anthropometry",
        "C. Biodynamics",
        "D. Anthropology"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Myology. Myology is the study of muscle structure and function, including how muscles produce forces and motion in the human body."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the term for the physiological and biomechanical study of the mechanics of the human heart and its associated blood vessels?",
      options: ["A. Cardiology", "B. Hematology", "C. Angiology", "D. Myology"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Angiology. Angiology is the branch of medicine and biomechanics that focuses on the study of the mechanics of the human heart and its associated blood vessels.")
];

List<QuestionModel> CAD = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. What does CAD stand for in the context of design and engineering?",
      options: [
        "Centralized Architecture Database",
        "Computer-Aided Design",
        "Creative Architecture Drawing",
        "Complex Algorithm Development"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "CAD stands for Computer-Aided Design, a technology used for designing and creating digital models of physical objects."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. In CAD software, what is the purpose of the 'extrude' tool?",
      options: [
        "To create 2D sketches",
        "To add material or depth to a 3D shape",
        "To apply colors and textures",
        "To measure distances"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The 'extrude' tool is used to add material or depth to a 3D shape, effectively turning 2D sketches into 3D objects."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. Which file format is commonly used for exchanging CAD drawings and models between different software applications?",
      options: [
        "PDF (Portable Document Format)",
        "DOCX (Microsoft Word Document)",
        "CSV (Comma-Separated Values)",
        "DXF (Drawing Exchange Format)"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "DXF (Drawing Exchange Format) is a common file format for exchanging CAD drawings and models between different software applications."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. What is the primary benefit of parametric modeling in CAD design?",
      options: [
        "It simplifies the design process",
        "It allows for direct 3D printing",
        "It uses only basic geometric shapes",
        "It enables design changes and updates"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Parametric modeling in CAD design allows for design changes and updates by capturing design intent and relationships between elements."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "5. In CAD, what does 'rendering' refer to?",
      options: [
        "The initial design phase",
        "Creating a 3D model from 2D sketches",
        "Generating a photorealistic image of a 3D model",
        "Measuring distances and angles"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Rendering in CAD refers to generating a photorealistic image of a 3D model, often used for presentations and visualizations."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. Which CAD tool is specifically designed for creating architectural designs and floor plans?",
      options: ["AutoCAD", "SolidWorks", "CATIA", "Blender"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "AutoCAD is a CAD tool specifically designed for creating architectural designs and floor plans."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the purpose of 'constraints' in parametric CAD modeling?",
      options: [
        "To add random design elements",
        "To limit the use of colors in the design",
        "To define relationships and rules for geometric shapes",
        "To create artistic renderings"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Constraints in parametric CAD modeling are used to define relationships and rules for geometric shapes, ensuring that they maintain specific properties or proportions."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. Which term is often used in CAD to describe a 3D model created by combining primitive shapes like cubes, spheres, and cylinders?",
      options: [
        "Parametric model",
        "Bézier curve",
        "Polygon mesh",
        "NURBS surface"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "A 'polygon mesh' is a term used in CAD to describe a 3D model created by combining primitive shapes like cubes, spheres, and cylinders."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "9. What is the role of 'layer management' in CAD software?",
      options: [
        "To manage the software's performance",
        "To categorize and organize elements in the design",
        "To add a 3D effect to the model",
        "To control the printing process"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Layer management in CAD software is used to categorize and organize elements in the design, making it easier to work with complex models."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which of the following is a common feature in CAD software that allows you to create a duplicate of an object at a specific distance and orientation?",
      options: [
        "Copy-Paste function",
        "Clone tool",
        "Mirror command",
        "Group and Ungroup"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The 'Mirror' command is a common feature in CAD software that allows you to create a duplicate of an object at a specific distance and orientation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "11. What is the primary purpose of CAD libraries or 'blocks'?",
      options: [
        "To display pop-up ads",
        "To store design data on a cloud server",
        "To provide pre-made and reusable design elements",
        "To secure CAD software from unauthorized access"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "CAD libraries or 'blocks' provide pre-made and reusable design elements, saving time and effort in the design process."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the primary function of the 'boolean operations' in CAD?",
      options: [
        "To perform logical operations",
        "To create user interfaces",
        "To analyze stress and strain",
        "To modify 3D shapes using union, subtraction, and intersection"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Boolean operations in CAD are used to modify 3D shapes through union, subtraction, and intersection, allowing for complex shape manipulation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "13. In CAD, what is 'parametric design' known for?",
      options: [
        "Its inability to handle complex geometries",
        "Its reliance on artistic design principles",
        "Its use of predefined equations and constraints",
        "Its focus on aesthetic appeal"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Parametric design in CAD is known for its use of predefined equations and constraints to create and modify designs."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "14. What is 'BIM' in the context of CAD and architecture?",
      options: [
        "Basic Interior Modeling",
        "Building Information Modeling",
        "Biometric Identity Measurement",
        "Binary Image Manipulation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "'BIM' stands for Building Information Modeling, a process that involves creating and managing digital representations of physical and functional characteristics of a building or infrastructure."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "15. What does 'CAM' stand for when it complements CAD?",
      options: [
        "Computer-Aided Mathematics",
        "Computer-Aided Manufacturing",
        "Computer Animation Modeling",
        "Creative Artistic Modeling"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "'CAM' stands for Computer-Aided Manufacturing, which is the use of software to control machine tools and 3D printers in the manufacturing process."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. Which CAD software is known for its use in industrial and mechanical design, offering parametric modeling capabilities?",
      options: ["AutoCAD", "Blender", "SketchUp", "SolidWorks"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "SolidWorks is known for its use in industrial and mechanical design and offers parametric modeling capabilities."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the primary advantage of 3D CAD modeling over 2D CAD design?",
      options: [
        "Higher file compatibility",
        "Faster rendering times",
        "Improved accuracy and visualization",
        "Lower hardware requirements"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "3D CAD modeling offers improved accuracy and visualization, allowing for better understanding and representation of complex designs."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "18. In CAD, what does 'NURBS' refer to?",
      options: [
        "Non-Uniform Rational B-Splines",
        "Numerical User Resource-Based System",
        "Newly Unified Rendering Standards",
        "Natural User Reaction to CAD Systems"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "'NURBS' stands for Non-Uniform Rational B-Splines, a mathematical model used in CAD for creating and representing curves and surfaces."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the primary purpose of 'assembly modeling' in CAD?",
      options: [
        "To create artistic designs",
        "To combine multiple 2D sketches into one",
        "To manage and visualize complex assemblies of components",
        "To measure the weight of a design"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Assembly modeling in CAD is used to manage and visualize complex assemblies of components, allowing for accurate representations of how parts fit together."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What role does 'constraints' play in 2D sketching in CAD software?",
      options: [
        "Constraints are not relevant in 2D sketching.",
        "Constraints help to limit the file size.",
        "Constraints are used to define relationships between sketch elements.",
        "Constraints are used to apply colors to sketches."
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Constraints in 2D sketching are used to define relationships between sketch elements, ensuring that they maintain specific positions and sizes.")
];

List<QuestionModel> Computational = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. What is Computational Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. A branch of mathematics",
        "B. The study of physical materials only",
        "C. The application of numerical methods to solve engineering problems",
        "D. The study of computational devices"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. The application of numerical methods to solve engineering problems. Computational Mechanics is a field that involves using numerical methods and computational tools to solve engineering and physical problems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. What is the primary advantage of using computational methods in Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. Reduced accuracy",
        "B. Inability to model complex systems",
        "C. Speed and efficiency",
        "D. Limited applicability"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Speed and efficiency. Computational methods in Mechanics offer the advantage of solving complex problems more quickly and efficiently than traditional analytical methods."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. Which mathematical concept is at the core of computational simulations in Mechanics?",
      options: ["A. Geometry", "B. Trigonometry", "C. Algebra", "D. Calculus"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Calculus. Calculus is a fundamental mathematical concept that plays a crucial role in computational simulations, as it deals with rates of change and integration."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. What is the primary purpose of Finite Element Analysis (FEA) in Computational Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. To study thermodynamics",
        "B. To analyze the motion of celestial bodies",
        "C. To model physical structures and solve stress and deformation problems",
        "D. To perform quantum calculations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To model physical structures and solve stress and deformation problems. FEA is widely used in Computational Mechanics to model and analyze structures under various loads and conditions."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What is the role of a mesh in Finite Element Analysis (FEA)?",
      options: [
        "A. To represent the material's color",
        "B. To measure the density of the material",
        "C. To divide a complex geometry into smaller, simpler elements",
        "D. To calculate temperature changes in materials"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To divide a complex geometry into smaller, simpler elements. In FEA, a mesh is used to discretize a complex structure into smaller elements for analysis."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. Which type of problems can Computational Mechanics address?",
      options: [
        "A. Only linear problems",
        "B. Only static problems",
        "C. Both linear and nonlinear problems",
        "D. Only problems with exact analytical solutions"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Both linear and nonlinear problems. Computational Mechanics can address a wide range of problems, including both linear and nonlinear ones, making it a versatile tool for engineering analysis."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the primary goal of a numerical solver in Computational Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. To determine the material's color",
        "B. To provide a solution to a mathematical model of a physical problem",
        "C. To measure the density of the material",
        "D. To analyze the temperature changes in materials"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To provide a solution to a mathematical model of a physical problem. Numerical solvers in Computational Mechanics aim to provide solutions to mathematical models that represent physical problems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the primary benefit of using numerical methods in Computational Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. Lack of precision",
        "B. Reduced computational efficiency",
        "C. Ability to handle complex geometry and boundary conditions",
        "D. Limited modeling capabilities"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Ability to handle complex geometry and boundary conditions. Numerical methods in Computational Mechanics are well-suited for handling complex geometries and a wide range of boundary conditions."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. In Computational Mechanics, what does the term 'convergence' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. A geometric shape",
        "B. A lack of mathematical solutions",
        "C. The process of iterative refinement to reach a stable solution",
        "D. A complex equation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. The process of iterative refinement to reach a stable solution. Convergence in Computational Mechanics refers to the iterative process of refining a solution until it reaches a stable and accurate result."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. What is the primary limitation of numerical simulations in Computational Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. Inability to handle any type of physical problem",
        "B. Dependence on analytical solutions",
        "C. The potential for numerical errors and limitations",
        "D. Lack of computational efficiency"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. The potential for numerical errors and limitations. While powerful, numerical simulations can be subject to errors and limitations, particularly when dealing with highly complex or poorly conditioned problems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the main objective of a sensitivity analysis in Computational Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. To determine the material's color under stress",
        "B. To calculate temperature changes in materials",
        "C. To evaluate the effect of variations in input parameters on the model's output",
        "D. To analyze the motion of celestial bodies"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To evaluate the effect of variations in input parameters on the model's output. Sensitivity analysis in Computational Mechanics assesses how changes in input parameters affect the model's output and predictions."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. In Computational Mechanics, what is 'parallel processing' used for?",
      options: [
        "A. To determine the material's color",
        "B. To increase computational efficiency by using multiple processors or cores",
        "C. To measure the density of the material",
        "D. To analyze the temperature changes in materials"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To increase computational efficiency by using multiple processors or cores. Parallel processing in Computational Mechanics involves using multiple processors or cores to accelerate simulations and improve efficiency."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the primary role of boundary conditions in Computational Mechanics simulations?",
      options: [
        "A. To define the material's color",
        "B. To measure the density of the material",
        "C. To establish constraints and environmental conditions for the model",
        "D. To calculate temperature changes in materials"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To establish constraints and environmental conditions for the model. Boundary conditions in Computational Mechanics simulations define the constraints and environmental conditions that affect the behavior of the model."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What is the term for the process of refining a numerical solution by iteratively reducing the error between the numerical and exact solutions?",
      options: [
        "A. Accuracy enhancement",
        "B. Convergence",
        "C. Approximation",
        "D. Overshoot correction"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Convergence. Convergence is the process of iteratively reducing the error between the numerical solution and the exact solution, leading to a more accurate result."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. In Computational Mechanics, what does the term 'post-processing' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. Evaluating the density of materials",
        "B. Analyzing the temperature changes in materials",
        "C. The analysis of simulation results to obtain engineering quantities of interest",
        "D. Calculating the motion of celestial bodies"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. The analysis of simulation results to obtain engineering quantities of interest. Post-processing in Computational Mechanics involves analyzing simulation results to extract specific engineering quantities of interest."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the primary application of Computational Mechanics in the field of aerospace engineering?",
      options: [
        "A. Analyzing financial data",
        "B. Studying marine life",
        "C. Simulating fluid dynamics in aircraft design",
        "D. Analyzing agricultural patterns"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Simulating fluid dynamics in aircraft design. Computational Mechanics is used extensively in aerospace engineering to simulate fluid dynamics and optimize aircraft design."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the primary advantage of using Computational Mechanics for structural analysis?",
      options: [
        "A. Limited ability to model complex structures",
        "B. Reduced accuracy",
        "C. Ability to analyze and optimize complex structures",
        "D. Dependence on physical experiments"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Ability to analyze and optimize complex structures. Computational Mechanics is advantageous for structural analysis due to its capability to model and optimize complex structures efficiently."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. In Computational Mechanics, what is 'pre-processing' used for?",
      options: [
        "A. Analyzing temperature changes in materials",
        "B. Defining simulation boundary conditions",
        "C. Evaluating the density of materials",
        "D. Calculating financial data"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Defining simulation boundary conditions. Pre-processing in Computational Mechanics involves setting up the simulation, defining boundary conditions, and preparing the model for analysis."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the term for a numerical technique used to solve partial differential equations in Computational Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. Algebra",
        "B. Geometry",
        "C. Finite Element Method (FEM)",
        "D. Calculus"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Finite Element Method (FEM). The Finite Element Method (FEM) is a numerical technique commonly used to solve partial differential equations in Computational Mechanics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the primary advantage of using numerical simulations in Computational Mechanics for material testing?",
      options: [
        "A. Inability to model different materials",
        "B. Dependence on analytical solutions",
        "C. Ability to model material behavior under various conditions and loads",
        "D. Lack of accuracy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Ability to model material behavior under various conditions and loads. Numerical simulations in Computational Mechanics allow for the modeling of material behavior under a wide range of conditions and loads, providing valuable insights for material testing.")
];

List<QuestionModel> controlsystem = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. What is the primary purpose of a control system?",
      options: [
        "A. To generate random signals",
        "B. To maintain a desired output in the presence of disturbances",
        "C. To analyze historical data",
        "D. To perform mathematical computations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To maintain a desired output in the presence of disturbances. Control systems are designed to regulate and stabilize a system's output, ensuring it remains at the desired level even when disturbances are present."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. Which of the following best describes an open-loop control system?",
      options: [
        "A. It relies on feedback to adjust the control input",
        "B. It operates without any control input",
        "C. It adjusts the control input based on sensor measurements",
        "D. It is highly sensitive to disturbances"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. It operates without any control input. In an open-loop control system, the control input is set without considering the system's output or feedback."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. What is the primary role of feedback in a closed-loop control system?",
      options: [
        "A. To generate control signals",
        "B. To introduce disturbances",
        "C. To adjust the control input based on the system's output",
        "D. To perform mathematical calculations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To adjust the control input based on the system's output. Feedback in a closed-loop control system provides information about the system's output, allowing the control input to be adjusted accordingly to maintain the desired output."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. What is the primary advantage of a proportional (P) controller in a control system?",
      options: [
        "A. It eliminates all disturbances",
        "B. It provides fast response but may lead to oscillations",
        "C. It reduces control input to zero",
        "D. It cannot be used in control systems"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. It provides fast response but may lead to oscillations. A proportional (P) controller offers a fast response to errors, but it can lead to oscillations when used alone."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What does the integral (I) controller in a control system primarily address?",
      options: [
        "A. Eliminating disturbances",
        "B. Reducing control input to zero",
        "C. Correcting steady-state errors",
        "D. Providing fast response"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Correcting steady-state errors. The integral (I) controller is used to eliminate steady-state errors in a control system by continuously adjusting the control input."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. In control systems, what is the primary function of the derivative (D) controller?",
      options: [
        "A. To eliminate disturbances",
        "B. To introduce oscillations",
        "C. To reduce control input to zero",
        "D. To dampen oscillations and improve system stability"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To dampen oscillations and improve system stability. The derivative (D) controller is used to dampen oscillations and improve the stability of the control system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the term for the difference between the desired output and the actual system output in a control system?",
      options: ["A. Setpoint", "B. Feedback", "C. Error", "D. Disturbance"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Error. The error represents the difference between the desired or reference output and the actual output in a control system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the primary purpose of a transfer function in control system analysis?",
      options: [
        "A. To introduce disturbances",
        "B. To measure control input",
        "C. To analyze historical data",
        "D. To describe the relationship between the input and output of a system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To describe the relationship between the input and output of a system. Transfer functions are used to mathematically describe the relationship between the input and output of a control system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is a 'pole' in the context of control system stability analysis?",
      options: [
        "A. A reference point for control input",
        "B. A point where control input is zero",
        "C. A characteristic of the system's transfer function that affects stability",
        "D. A type of control input signal"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. A characteristic of the system's transfer function that affects stability. In control system stability analysis, poles represent the locations in the complex plane that determine the system's stability."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "10. In control systems, what is meant by 'system response'?",
      options: [
        "A. The ability to eliminate all disturbances",
        "B. The way a system reacts to control input and disturbances",
        "C. The control input signal",
        "D. The setpoint value"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. The way a system reacts to control input and disturbances. System response refers to how a system reacts to control input and disturbances, including its transient and steady-state behavior."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. Which of the following terms describes the process of adjusting control parameters to achieve desired system performance?",
      options: [
        "A. Disturbance rejection",
        "B. Feedback control",
        "C. Control tuning",
        "D. Steady-state analysis"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Control tuning. Control tuning involves the process of adjusting control parameters to achieve the desired performance and stability of a control system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. In control systems, what is the term for an input signal used to test and analyze the system's behavior?",
      options: [
        "A. Setpoint",
        "B. Feedback signal",
        "C. Disturbance",
        "D. Test signal or input"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Test signal or input. A test signal or input is used to analyze and assess the behavior and performance of a control system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the primary function of a root locus plot in control system analysis?",
      options: [
        "A. To eliminate disturbances",
        "B. To provide control input",
        "C. To establish constraints and environmental conditions for the model",
        "D. To analyze the system's stability and behavior"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To analyze the system's stability and behavior. A root locus plot is used to analyze the stability and behavior of a control system by showing how the system's poles change with varying control parameters."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What is the term for a controller that adjusts the control input based on the difference between the desired output and the current output?",
      options: [
        "A. Proportional (P) controller",
        "B. Integral (I) controller",
        "C. Derivative (D) controller",
        "D. Closed-loop controller"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Closed-loop controller. A closed-loop controller adjusts the control input based on feedback from the system's output and the desired output to maintain control."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. In control systems, what is the term for the range of control input values over which the system's output remains stable and within acceptable limits?",
      options: [
        "A. Setpoint",
        "B. Control input",
        "C. Control signal",
        "D. Control bandwidth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Control bandwidth. Control bandwidth is the range of control input values over which the system's output remains stable and within acceptable limits."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the primary advantage of using a lead compensator in control system design?",
      options: [
        "A. Improved steady-state accuracy",
        "B. Increased sensitivity to disturbances",
        "C. Slower system response",
        "D. Decreased system stability"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Improved steady-state accuracy. A lead compensator is used to improve steady-state accuracy in a control system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. In control systems, what is the term for a signal or disturbance that affects the system's output but is not part of the controlled variable?",
      options: [
        "A. Setpoint",
        "B. Control input",
        "C. Disturbance",
        "D. Feedback signal"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Disturbance. A disturbance is a signal or external factor that affects the system's output but is not part of the controlled variable."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the primary purpose of a Nyquist plot in control system analysis?",
      options: [
        "A. To eliminate disturbances",
        "B. To measure control input",
        "C. To analyze historical data",
        "D. To assess the stability and behavior of a system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To assess the stability and behavior of a system. A Nyquist plot is used to assess the stability and behavior of a control system by providing information about the system's frequency response."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the term for the characteristic of a control system that determines how quickly it responds to changes in the input or disturbances?",
      options: [
        "A. Steady-state error",
        "B. Control bandwidth",
        "C. Setpoint",
        "D. Transient response"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Transient response. Transient response describes how quickly a control system responds to changes in the input or disturbances before reaching a new steady-state."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. In control systems, what is the primary function of a lead-lag compensator?",
      options: [
        "A. To eliminate all disturbances",
        "B. To provide fast response",
        "C. To improve both steady-state accuracy and transient response",
        "D. To introduce oscillations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To improve both steady-state accuracy and transient response. A lead-lag compensator is designed to improve both steady-state accuracy and transient response in a control system.")
];

List<QuestionModel> fluidflow = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. What is the primary characteristic of a Newtonian fluid?",
      options: [
        "A. Constant viscosity with changing shear rate",
        "B. Viscosity dependent on pressure",
        "C. Viscosity increasing exponentially with temperature",
        "D. No viscosity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Constant viscosity with changing shear rate. Newtonian fluids maintain a constant viscosity regardless of changes in shear rate."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "2. In fluid flow, what does Reynolds number (Re) describe?",
      options: [
        "A. Flow rate",
        "B. Viscosity",
        "C. Turbulence and flow regime",
        "D. Fluid density"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Turbulence and flow regime. Reynolds number (Re) is used to determine the flow regime, whether laminar or turbulent, based on the ratio of inertial forces to viscous forces."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. What is the equation for calculating the pressure drop (ΔP) in a fluid flowing through a pipe?",
      options: [
        "A. ΔP = ρgh",
        "B. ΔP = ηV",
        "C. ΔP = f (L/D) (ρV²/2)",
        "D. ΔP = P₁ - P₂"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. ΔP = f (L/D) (ρV²/2). The Darcy-Weisbach equation is used to calculate pressure drop in a pipe based on factors like pipe length, diameter, fluid density, velocity, and friction factor (f)."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which of the following factors can lead to increased friction losses in fluid flow through pipes?",
      options: [
        "A. Smoother pipe surface",
        "B. Higher flow velocity",
        "C. Decreased fluid viscosity",
        "D. Larger pipe diameter"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Higher flow velocity. Increased flow velocity can lead to higher friction losses due to increased shear stress at the pipe walls."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What is the primary function of a Pitot tube in fluid flow measurement?",
      options: [
        "A. Measure flow rate",
        "B. Measure fluid density",
        "C. Measure fluid velocity",
        "D. Measure fluid pressure"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Measure fluid velocity. A Pitot tube is used to measure fluid velocity by measuring the difference in pressure between the stagnation point and the fluid dynamic pressure."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What is the term for the point in a pipe flow where the fluid velocity is at its maximum and pressure is at its minimum?",
      options: [
        "A. Stagnation point",
        "B. Vortex point",
        "C. Critical point",
        "D. Center point"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Stagnation point. The stagnation point is where the fluid velocity is maximum, and pressure is minimum."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. Which fluid flow pattern is characterized by smooth and orderly layers of fluid with minimal mixing?",
      options: [
        "A. Laminar flow",
        "B. Turbulent flow",
        "C. Transitional flow",
        "D. Compressible flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Laminar flow. Laminar flow is characterized by smooth and orderly layers of fluid with minimal mixing between adjacent layers."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. In fluid dynamics, what is the Hagen–Poiseuille equation used for?",
      options: [
        "A. To calculate Reynolds number",
        "B. To calculate flow rate",
        "C. To calculate pressure drop in laminar flow",
        "D. To calculate turbulence intensity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To calculate pressure drop in laminar flow. The Hagen–Poiseuille equation is used to calculate pressure drop in laminar pipe flow."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is the primary cause of turbulent flow in a fluid system?",
      options: [
        "A. High fluid viscosity",
        "B. Low flow velocity",
        "C. High Reynolds number",
        "D. Smooth pipe surface"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. High Reynolds number. Turbulent flow occurs at high Reynolds numbers, indicating the dominance of inertial forces over viscous forces."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. What does the Bernoulli's equation describe in fluid dynamics?",
      options: [
        "A. Flow rate through a pipe",
        "B. Fluid density",
        "C. The relationship between pressure, velocity, and potential energy in a fluid",
        "D. Fluid viscosity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. The relationship between pressure, velocity, and potential energy in a fluid. Bernoulli's equation describes how the sum of pressure, kinetic energy, and potential energy remains constant along a streamline in an inviscid, incompressible flow."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the term for the resistance offered by a fluid to deformation or flow?",
      options: ["A. Viscosity", "B. Density", "C. Velocity", "D. Friction"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Viscosity. Viscosity is the measure of a fluid's resistance to deformation or flow."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the primary factor affecting the laminar-turbulent transition in fluid flow?",
      options: [
        "A. Pipe diameter",
        "B. Flow velocity",
        "C. Fluid density",
        "D. Viscosity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Flow velocity. The transition from laminar to turbulent flow is primarily influenced by the flow velocity, indicated by the Reynolds number."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. In a converging-diverging nozzle, what type of flow occurs at the throat?",
      options: [
        "A. Subsonic flow",
        "B. Supersonic flow",
        "C. Laminar flow",
        "D. Turbulent flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Supersonic flow. In a converging-diverging nozzle, supersonic flow occurs at the throat, where the flow velocity reaches the speed of sound."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What happens to fluid pressure as it flows through a converging section of a pipe or nozzle?",
      options: [
        "A. Increases",
        "B. Decreases",
        "C. Remains constant",
        "D. Depends on the fluid type"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Increases. As fluid flows through a converging section, its velocity increases, resulting in a decrease in pressure due to Bernoulli's principle."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What is the primary purpose of a Venturi tube in fluid flow measurement?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase flow rate",
        "B. Decrease flow velocity",
        "C. Measure fluid density",
        "D. Accurately measure flow rate"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Accurately measure flow rate. A Venturi tube is designed to accurately measure fluid flow rates by utilizing the principle of pressure differences in constricted flow areas."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. Which type of pump is commonly used to transport viscous fluids like oil and slurry?",
      options: [
        "A. Centrifugal pump",
        "B. Diaphragm pump",
        "C. Gear pump",
        "D. Reciprocating pump"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Gear pump. Gear pumps are often used to transport viscous fluids due to their ability to handle high viscosity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the primary factor that determines whether a flow in a pipe is considered laminar or turbulent?",
      options: [
        "A. Pipe material",
        "B. Temperature",
        "C. Flow rate",
        "D. Pipe diameter"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Pipe diameter. The transition from laminar to turbulent flow is heavily influenced by the pipe's diameter, specifically the Reynolds number."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the main principle behind the operation of a hydraulic jack for lifting heavy loads?",
      options: [
        "A. Archimedes' principle",
        "B. Pascal's principle",
        "C. Bernoulli's principle",
        "D. Hooke's law"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Pascal's principle. Hydraulic jacks work on Pascal's principle, which states that a change in pressure applied at any point in an enclosed fluid is transmitted undiminished throughout the fluid."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the primary application of a flowmeter in fluid flow analysis?",
      options: [
        "A. Measure pipe diameter",
        "B. Measure fluid density",
        "C. Measure fluid velocity or flow rate",
        "D. Measure pipe length"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Measure fluid velocity or flow rate. Flowmeters are used to measure fluid velocity or flow rate in various applications."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the primary advantage of using a differential pressure flowmeter in fluid flow measurement?",
      options: [
        "A. High accuracy in measuring low flow rates",
        "B. Simplicity and ease of installation",
        "C. Ability to measure non-newtonian fluids",
        "D. Resistance to corrosion"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Simplicity and ease of installation. Differential pressure flowmeters are often chosen for their simplicity and ease of installation in various fluid flow applications."),
];

List<QuestionModel> fluidmechanics = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. What is the property of a fluid that represents its resistance to flow?",
      options: ["Density", "Viscosity", "Pressure", "Compressibility"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The property of a fluid that represents its resistance to flow is viscosity. Viscosity is a measure of a fluid's internal friction, and fluids with high viscosity flow more slowly than those with low viscosity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. In fluid mechanics, what is the term for the force per unit area exerted by a fluid on the walls of its container?",
      options: ["Weight", "Volume", "Pressure", "Density"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "In fluid mechanics, the term for the force per unit area exerted by a fluid on the walls of its container is pressure. Pressure is often expressed in units of pascals (Pa) or newtons per square meter (N/m²)."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. Which principle states that the pressure applied to an enclosed fluid is transmitted undiminished to all portions of the fluid and to the walls of its container?",
      options: [
        "Pascal's principle",
        "Bernoulli's principle",
        "Archimedes' principle",
        "Newton's third law"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "Pascal's principle states that the pressure applied to an enclosed fluid is transmitted undiminished to all portions of the fluid and to the walls of its container. It is the basis for hydraulic systems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. When an object is partially or wholly immersed in a fluid, it experiences an upward buoyant force. This force is equal to the weight of the displaced fluid and is described by which principle?",
      options: [
        "Pascal's principle",
        "Archimedes' principle",
        "Bernoulli's principle",
        "Newton's third law"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "When an object is partially or wholly immersed in a fluid, it experiences an upward buoyant force, which is equal to the weight of the displaced fluid. This principle is described by Archimedes' principle."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What is the term for the point at which the pressure in a fluid is the same in all directions, allowing an object to float without sinking or rising?",
      options: [
        "Center of gravity",
        "Center of pressure",
        "Neutral point",
        "Center of buoyancy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The term for the point at which the pressure in a fluid is the same in all directions, allowing an object to float without sinking or rising, is the neutral point. It is a critical concept in buoyancy."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What is the name for the measurement of the upward force exerted by a fluid on an immersed object, which opposes the weight of the object?",
      options: ["Pressure", "Volume", "Buoyancy", "Viscosity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The measurement of the upward force exerted by a fluid on an immersed object, which opposes the weight of the object, is called buoyancy. It is responsible for objects floating in fluids."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. According to Bernoulli's principle, as the velocity of a fluid increases, its pressure:",
      options: [
        "Decreases",
        "Increases",
        "Remains constant",
        "Varies unpredictably"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "According to Bernoulli's principle, as the velocity of a fluid increases, its pressure decreases. This principle is used to explain the relationship between fluid speed and pressure in various fluid flow scenarios."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the term for a fluid's resistance to shear or tensile stresses, resulting in its deformation or flow?",
      options: ["Viscosity", "Pressure", "Density", "Compressibility"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The term for a fluid's resistance to shear or tensile stresses, resulting in its deformation or flow, is viscosity. Viscosity is a crucial property in fluid mechanics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. When a fluid flows through a pipe, what happens to its velocity and pressure as the pipe's cross-sectional area decreases?",
      options: [
        "Velocity increases, pressure increases",
        "Velocity increases, pressure decreases",
        "Velocity decreases, pressure increases",
        "Velocity decreases, pressure decreases"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "When a fluid flows through a pipe, if the cross-sectional area decreases (constriction), the velocity of the fluid increases, but the pressure decreases. This phenomenon is explained by Bernoulli's principle."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. What is the term for the point at which the flow velocity of a fluid becomes equal to the speed of sound in that fluid, causing a sudden drop in pressure and a potential shockwave?",
      options: [
        "Critical point",
        "Choked flow",
        "Stagnation point",
        "Sonic point"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The term for the point at which the flow velocity of a fluid becomes equal to the speed of sound in that fluid, causing a sudden drop in pressure and a potential shockwave, is choked flow. It is a critical condition in fluid dynamics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the term for a fluid's ability to transmit pressure and transmit forces in a confined space?",
      options: [
        "Incompressibility",
        "Compressibility",
        "Hydraulic efficiency",
        "Bulk modulus"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The term for a fluid's ability to transmit pressure and transmit forces in a confined space is bulk modulus. It measures the fluid's resistance to compression."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. When a fluid flows over a surface, what is the term for the force per unit area exerted by the fluid on the surface, parallel to the flow direction?",
      options: [
        "Drag force",
        "Buoyant force",
        "Pressure force",
        "Viscous force"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "When a fluid flows over a surface, the force per unit area exerted by the fluid on the surface, parallel to the flow direction, is called the viscous force. It is responsible for the effect of viscosity in fluid flow."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the term for the study of the behavior of fluids at rest or in equilibrium?",
      options: ["Dynamics", "Hydraulics", "Thermodynamics", "Statics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The term for the study of the behavior of fluids at rest or in equilibrium is statics. It is a fundamental branch of fluid mechanics that deals with fluid properties and equilibrium conditions."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. Which fluid property measures the resistance of a fluid to compressibility, indicating its ability to maintain constant density under pressure?",
      options: ["Viscosity", "Density", "Bulk modulus", "Pressure"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The fluid property that measures the resistance of a fluid to compressibility, indicating its ability to maintain constant density under pressure, is bulk modulus. It is a key property in fluid behavior."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What is the term for the condition in a fluid flow where the fluid particles move in parallel layers with minimal mixing between them?",
      options: [
        "Laminar flow",
        "Turbulent flow",
        "Steady flow",
        "Unsteady flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The condition in a fluid flow where the fluid particles move in parallel layers with minimal mixing between them is called laminar flow. It is characterized by smooth, orderly motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the term for the study of the motion and behavior of fluids, particularly in motion or flow situations?",
      options: ["Statics", "Hydraulics", "Kinematics", "Dynamics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The term for the study of the motion and behavior of fluids, particularly in motion or flow situations, is dynamics. It is a key branch of fluid mechanics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the name for the condition in a fluid flow where the fluid particles exhibit chaotic and irregular motion, causing mixing and turbulence?",
      options: [
        "Laminar flow",
        "Turbulent flow",
        "Steady flow",
        "Unsteady flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The condition in a fluid flow where the fluid particles exhibit chaotic and irregular motion, causing mixing and turbulence, is called turbulent flow. It is characterized by disorderly motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. In the context of fluid mechanics, what is the term for the ratio of the dynamic pressure to the static pressure of a fluid in motion?",
      options: [
        "Reynolds number",
        "Mach number",
        "Froude number",
        "Prandtl number"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "In the context of fluid mechanics, the term for the ratio of the dynamic pressure to the static pressure of a fluid in motion is the Mach number. It is used to describe the compressibility effects of high-speed flows."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. When a fluid flows through a pipe, what term describes the condition where the flow becomes unsteady and changes with time?",
      options: [
        "Steady flow",
        "Laminar flow",
        "Turbulent flow",
        "Unsteady flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "When a fluid flows through a pipe and the flow becomes unsteady and changes with time, it is described as unsteady flow. It contrasts with steady flow, which is time-invariant."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the term for the ratio of inertial forces to viscous forces in a fluid flow and is used to predict the flow's behavior?",
      options: [
        "Reynolds number",
        "Mach number",
        "Froude number",
        "Prandtl number"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The term for the ratio of inertial forces to viscous forces in a fluid flow, which is used to predict the flow's behavior, is the Reynolds number. It is a fundamental parameter in fluid dynamics and determines whether the flow is laminar or turbulent.")
];

List<QuestionModel> fluidpowersystem = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. In fluid power systems, which fluid is commonly used due to its incompressible nature and ability to transmit force effectively?",
      options: ["Gasoline", "Water", "Air", "Steam"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Air is commonly used in fluid power systems due to its incompressible nature and effectiveness in transmitting force."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. What type of fluid power system uses pressurized fluids to create motion, typically found in heavy machinery and construction equipment?",
      options: [
        "Pneumatic system",
        "Hydraulic system",
        "Piston system",
        "Compressed air system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Hydraulic systems use pressurized fluids to create motion and are commonly found in heavy machinery and construction equipment."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. Which of the following components is commonly used to control the direction of fluid flow in a hydraulic system?",
      options: ["Hydraulic cylinder", "Flow meter", "Check valve", "Filter"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "A check valve is commonly used to control the direction of fluid flow in a hydraulic system, allowing flow in one direction while blocking it in the other."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. What is the primary advantage of a pneumatic system over a hydraulic system?",
      options: [
        "Higher power density",
        "Lower noise levels",
        "Greater precision",
        "Improved energy efficiency"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Pneumatic systems are often quieter than hydraulic systems, making them suitable for noise-sensitive applications."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. In a hydraulic system, which component is responsible for converting fluid pressure into mechanical motion?",
      options: [
        "Flow control valve",
        "Reservoir tank",
        "Hydraulic pump",
        "Hydraulic cylinder"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The hydraulic cylinder is responsible for converting fluid pressure into mechanical motion in a hydraulic system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What is the purpose of a pressure relief valve in a fluid power system?",
      options: [
        "To maintain a constant flow rate",
        "To regulate temperature",
        "To control fluid direction",
        "To prevent overpressure and damage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "A pressure relief valve in a fluid power system is used to prevent overpressure and potential damage by relieving excess pressure when it exceeds a set limit."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the primary function of an accumulator in a hydraulic system?",
      options: [
        "To store and release hydraulic fluid",
        "To filter the hydraulic fluid",
        "To control fluid direction",
        "To measure fluid flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "An accumulator in a hydraulic system stores hydraulic fluid and releases it when needed to maintain pressure or supplement the system's power supply."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. Which of the following fluid power components is used to change the rate of fluid flow and control the speed of an actuator?",
      options: [
        "Pressure gauge",
        "Directional control valve",
        "Flow control valve",
        "Check valve"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "A flow control valve is used to change the rate of fluid flow and control the speed of an actuator in a fluid power system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. In a pneumatic system, what is the function of an air compressor?",
      options: [
        "To store compressed air",
        "To release air pressure",
        "To control fluid direction",
        "To generate compressed air"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "An air compressor in a pneumatic system is used to generate compressed air, which is a source of power for the system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. What type of pump is commonly used in hydraulic systems to provide a continuous flow of hydraulic fluid?",
      options: [
        "Piston pump",
        "Gear pump",
        "Reciprocating pump",
        "Centrifugal pump"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Gear pumps are commonly used in hydraulic systems to provide a continuous flow of hydraulic fluid."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. The force applied to a fluid power system actuator is a result of:",
      options: [
        "The pressure difference between inlet and outlet",
        "The temperature of the fluid",
        "The fluid density",
        "The flow rate of the fluid"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The force applied to a fluid power system actuator is a result of the pressure difference between the inlet and outlet of the system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the primary advantage of using pneumatic systems in environments with explosive materials or gases?",
      options: [
        "Higher power density",
        "Low risk of ignition",
        "Greater precision",
        "Improved energy efficiency"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Pneumatic systems are less likely to cause ignition in environments with explosive materials or gases due to their low risk of ignition."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. Which of the following is a common application of fluid power systems?",
      options: [
        "Computer programming",
        "Car entertainment systems",
        "Automated manufacturing equipment",
        "Household appliances"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Automated manufacturing equipment often utilizes fluid power systems for various functions like lifting, moving, and pressing."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "14. In fluid power systems, what is the role of a filter?",
      options: [
        "To direct fluid flow",
        "To store hydraulic fluid",
        "To regulate temperature",
        "To remove contaminants"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "A filter in a fluid power system is used to remove contaminants and particles from the hydraulic fluid to maintain system cleanliness."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What is the primary function of a directional control valve in a fluid power system?",
      options: [
        "To regulate pressure",
        "To generate compressed air",
        "To control fluid direction",
        "To measure fluid flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "A directional control valve in a fluid power system is used to control the direction of fluid flow within the system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. Which of the following is a disadvantage of pneumatic systems when compared to hydraulic systems?",
      options: [
        "Lower noise levels",
        "Greater precision",
        "Lower power density",
        "Higher risk of contamination"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Pneumatic systems typically have lower power density compared to hydraulic systems, meaning they provide less power per unit of size and weight."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. Which of the following factors is crucial when selecting a fluid for use in a fluid power system?",
      options: [
        "Color of the fluid",
        "Price of the fluid",
        "Density of the fluid",
        "Viscosity of the fluid"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Viscosity is a crucial factor when selecting a fluid for use in a fluid power system, as it affects the fluid's flow and performance."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the primary advantage of a fluid power system over an electrical system in certain applications?",
      options: [
        "Higher efficiency",
        "Lower maintenance requirements",
        "Lower cost of components",
        "Greater safety in hazardous environments"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Fluid power systems are often preferred over electrical systems in hazardous environments due to their greater safety and reduced risk of electrical sparks."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the primary function of a pressure gauge in a fluid power system?",
      options: [
        "To control fluid direction",
        "To measure fluid flow",
        "To regulate pressure",
        "To display fluid pressure"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "A pressure gauge in a fluid power system is used to display and measure the fluid pressure within the system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. In a hydraulic system, why is it important to have a hydraulic reservoir or tank?",
      options: [
        "To generate hydraulic fluid",
        "To store and release hydraulic fluid",
        "To regulate temperature",
        "To control fluid direction"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "A hydraulic reservoir or tank is used to store and release hydraulic fluid as needed to maintain system pressure and ensure a continuous supply of fluid.")
];

List<QuestionModel> heattransfer = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. Heat transfer that occurs due to the movement of a fluid, such as air or water, is called:",
      options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Radiation", "Insulation"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Convection is the heat transfer mechanism that occurs due to the movement of a fluid. It involves the transfer of heat through the motion of the fluid itself."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. The primary method of heat transfer in solids like metal rods is called:",
      options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Radiation", "Advection"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "Conduction is the primary method of heat transfer in solids like metal rods. It involves the transfer of heat through direct contact between particles in a material."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. The transfer of heat in the form of electromagnetic waves, such as from the sun to the Earth, is called:",
      options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Radiation", "Advection"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Radiation is the transfer of heat in the form of electromagnetic waves. It does not require a medium for heat transfer and can occur through a vacuum."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which of the following materials is a good conductor of heat?",
      options: ["Wood", "Plastic", "Aluminum", "Fiberglass"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Aluminum is a good conductor of heat. It quickly transfers heat due to the high thermal conductivity of the material."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. The rate of heat transfer depends on several factors, including the temperature difference, material properties, and the surface area. What is this rate of heat transfer known as?",
      options: [
        "Thermal inertia",
        "Heat capacity",
        "Thermal conductivity",
        "Thermal resistance"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The rate of heat transfer depends on several factors, and it is known as thermal resistance. It is often used in calculations involving heat transfer."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. Which of the following is a poor conductor of heat and is often used for thermal insulation?",
      options: ["Copper", "Stainless steel", "Fiberglass", "Silver"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Fiberglass is a poor conductor of heat and is often used for thermal insulation due to its low thermal conductivity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. The process of reducing heat transfer by trapping air or other gases in a material is known as:",
      options: ["Conduction", "Radiation", "Insulation", "Convection"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Insulation is the process of reducing heat transfer by trapping air or other gases in a material, creating a barrier to heat flow."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. In a thermos bottle, what is the purpose of the vacuum layer between the inner and outer walls?",
      options: [
        "To enhance conduction",
        "To promote radiation",
        "To encourage convection",
        "To minimize heat transfer"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The vacuum layer in a thermos bottle is designed to minimize heat transfer by reducing conduction, convection, and radiation, thus keeping the contents hot or cold."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. Which mode of heat transfer does not require a material medium for transmission and can occur in a vacuum?",
      options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Radiation", "Advection"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Radiation is the mode of heat transfer that does not require a material medium for transmission and can occur in a vacuum, such as the transfer of heat from the sun to Earth."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. The principle of using a reflective surface, such as a shiny aluminum foil, to reduce heat transfer through radiation is utilized in:",
      options: [
        "Solar panels",
        "Thermal insulation",
        "Radiant floor heating",
        "Reflective insulation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Reflective insulation utilizes a reflective surface, such as shiny aluminum foil, to reduce heat transfer through radiation, helping maintain comfortable indoor temperatures."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. In which industrial process is the term 'heat exchanger' commonly used to efficiently transfer thermal energy from one fluid to another?",
      options: [
        "Brewing coffee",
        "Refrigeration",
        "Electric heating",
        "Chemical manufacturing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Heat exchangers are commonly used in chemical manufacturing processes to efficiently transfer thermal energy from one fluid to another."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. The transfer of heat between a hot and cold fluid within a pipeline or a duct is a typical application of:",
      options: [
        "Thermal insulation",
        "Heat conduction",
        "Heat exchangers",
        "Radiant heating"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The transfer of heat between a hot and cold fluid within a pipeline or a duct is a typical application of heat exchangers, which improve energy efficiency."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. Which of the following is not a primary method of heat transfer?",
      options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Insulation", "Radiation"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Insulation is not a primary method of heat transfer but a method to reduce heat transfer through conduction, convection, and radiation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. In a home heating system, what is the purpose of a thermostat?",
      options: [
        "To regulate insulation",
        "To control radiation",
        "To adjust conduction",
        "To maintain a set temperature"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "A thermostat in a home heating system is used to maintain a set temperature by controlling when the heating system turns on and off."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. The concept of the 'greenhouse effect' is often used to explain the trapping of heat in the Earth's atmosphere. Which mode of heat transfer is primarily responsible for this effect?",
      options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Radiation", "Insulation"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The greenhouse effect is primarily due to the radiation of heat being trapped in the Earth's atmosphere, which warms the planet."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "16. The rate of heat transfer is often measured in units of:",
      options: ["Kelvin", "Watt-hours", "Moles", "British thermal units (BTU)"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The rate of heat transfer is often measured in units of British thermal units (BTU) or joules per second (Watts)."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. Which of the following statements is true about heat transfer through convection?",
      options: [
        "It only occurs in liquids and gases",
        "It requires a material medium for transmission",
        "It is not influenced by temperature differences",
        "It can transfer heat in a vacuum"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Heat transfer through convection requires a material medium for transmission and can occur in liquids and gases but not in a vacuum."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. The material property that quantifies a substance's ability to conduct heat is known as:",
      options: [
        "Heat capacity",
        "Thermal resistance",
        "Heat transfer coefficient",
        "Thermal conductivity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The material property that quantifies a substance's ability to conduct heat is called thermal conductivity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. Which of the following is an example of natural convection?",
      options: [
        "Wind blowing through a window",
        "Hot air rising from a radiator",
        "Cooling a computer with a fan",
        "Heat transfer through a metal rod"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Hot air rising from a radiator is an example of natural convection, where warmer fluid (air) rises and cooler fluid sinks, creating a natural flow."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the name of the law that states the rate of heat transfer is directly proportional to the temperature difference between two objects and inversely proportional to the thermal resistance between them?",
      options: [
        "Newton's law of cooling",
        "Einstein's heat equation",
        "Faraday's thermal principle",
        "Fourier's law of conduction"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "Newton's law of cooling states that the rate of heat transfer is directly proportional to the temperature difference between two objects and inversely proportional to the thermal resistance between them.")
];

List<QuestionModel> Kinematicsanddynamics = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. What is the branch of mechanics that deals with the motion of objects without considering the forces that cause the motion?",
      options: ["Kinematics", "Dynamics", "Statics", "Thermodynamics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The branch of mechanics that deals with the motion of objects without considering the forces that cause the motion is called kinematics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. In kinematics, what is the term for the change in an object's position with respect to time?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "In kinematics, the term for the change in an object's position with respect to time is called displacement. It is a vector quantity that includes both magnitude and direction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. What is the study of the causes of motion and changes in motion called?",
      options: ["Kinematics", "Statics", "Dynamics", "Thermodynamics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The study of the causes of motion and changes in motion is called dynamics. It considers the forces and interactions that affect the motion of objects."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which of the following is an example of a vector quantity in kinematics?",
      options: ["Speed", "Time", "Distance", "Acceleration"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Acceleration is an example of a vector quantity in kinematics. Vector quantities have both magnitude and direction, and acceleration specifies how an object's velocity changes with time."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What is the term for the rate of change of an object's velocity with respect to time?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The rate of change of an object's velocity with respect to time is called acceleration. It indicates how quickly an object's velocity is changing."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. In kinematics, what is the area under a velocity-time graph equal to?",
      options: ["Distance traveled", "Speed", "Displacement", "Acceleration"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "In kinematics, the area under a velocity-time graph is equal to the distance traveled by the object. It represents the total path length."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "7. Which of the following is a scalar quantity in kinematics?",
      options: ["Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement", "Speed"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Speed is a scalar quantity in kinematics. Scalar quantities have magnitude but no direction, while vector quantities like velocity have both magnitude and direction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the term for the change in an object's velocity with respect to time?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The change in an object's velocity with respect to time is called acceleration. It indicates how the speed or direction of motion is changing."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is the term for the vector quantity that represents an object's change in position?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Displacement is the vector quantity that represents an object's change in position. It includes both the magnitude of the change and the direction of the change."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. What is the term for the rate of change of position with respect to time in kinematics?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The rate of change of position with respect to time in kinematics is called velocity. It is a vector quantity that describes the object's speed and direction of motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. Which of the following equations represents the relationship between displacement, initial velocity, time, and acceleration in kinematics?",
      options: [
        "s = ut + 1/2at^2",
        "s = ut + vt",
        "v = u + at",
        "v^2 = u^2 + 2as"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The equation s = ut + 1/2at^2 represents the relationship between displacement (s), initial velocity (u), time (t), and acceleration (a) in kinematics. It is one of the equations of motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the term for the study of objects at rest or in constant motion without acceleration?",
      options: ["Kinematics", "Statics", "Dynamics", "Thermodynamics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The study of objects at rest or in constant motion without acceleration is called statics. It is a branch of mechanics that deals with equilibrium."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. In kinematics, what is the term for the change in velocity with respect to time?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The change in velocity with respect to time is called acceleration in kinematics. It represents how an object's velocity is changing."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What is the term for the total path length traveled by an object in kinematics?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Distance"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The total path length traveled by an object in kinematics is called distance. It is a scalar quantity that does not specify direction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. Which of the following is an example of a scalar quantity in kinematics?",
      options: ["Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement", "Speed"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Speed is an example of a scalar quantity in kinematics. Scalar quantities have magnitude but no direction, unlike vector quantities like velocity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the term for the vector quantity that represents an object's change in velocity?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Acceleration is the vector quantity that represents an object's change in velocity. It describes how the object's speed or direction of motion is changing."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the term for the total length of the path traveled by an object in a specific direction in kinematics?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The total length of the path traveled by an object in a specific direction in kinematics is called displacement. It is a vector quantity that includes both magnitude and direction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. Which of the following equations represents the relationship between initial velocity, final velocity, acceleration, and displacement in kinematics?",
      options: [
        "s = ut + 1/2at^2",
        "s = ut + vt",
        "v = u + at",
        "v^2 = u^2 + 2as"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The equation s = ut + vt represents the relationship between initial velocity (u), final velocity (v), time (t), and acceleration (a) in kinematics. It is used to calculate displacement."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. In kinematics, what is the term for the change in position with respect to time?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "In kinematics, the change in position with respect to time is called velocity. It specifies the rate at which an object's position changes."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. Which of the following equations represents the relationship between initial velocity, final velocity, acceleration, and time in kinematics?",
      options: [
        "s = ut + 1/2at^2",
        "s = ut + vt",
        "v = u + at",
        "v^2 = u^2 + 2as"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The equation v = u + at represents the relationship between initial velocity (u), final velocity (v), acceleration (a), and time (t) in kinematics. It describes how an object's velocity changes over time.")
];

List<QuestionModel> machineElements = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. Which of the following machine elements is used to transmit power between two non-parallel and non-intersecting shafts?",
      options: ["A. Gear", "B. Belt", "C. Bearing", "D. Spring"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Belt. Belts are often used to transmit power between two non-parallel and non-intersecting shafts. They provide a flexible and reliable power transmission solution."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. What type of gear is known for its ability to change the direction of rotation between two shafts that intersect at 90 degrees?",
      options: [
        "A. Spur gear",
        "B. Helical gear",
        "C. Bevel gear",
        "D. Worm gear"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Bevel gear. Bevel gears are used to change the direction of rotation between two intersecting shafts at 90 degrees. They have conical-shaped teeth."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. Which type of bearing is commonly used to support radial loads in rotating machinery?",
      options: [
        "A. Ball bearing",
        "B. Roller bearing",
        "C. Thrust bearing",
        "D. Tapered bearing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Ball bearing. Ball bearings are commonly used to support radial loads in rotating machinery. They consist of rolling elements (balls) that reduce friction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "4. What is the primary purpose of a key in a machine element?",
      options: [
        "A. To reduce friction",
        "B. To align shafts",
        "C. To transmit power",
        "D. To dampen vibrations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To align shafts. Keys are used to ensure proper alignment between a shaft and a hub, preventing relative rotation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. In a reciprocating engine, what machine element is responsible for converting linear motion into rotary motion?",
      options: ["A. Pulley", "B. Gear", "C. Crankshaft", "D. Spline"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Crankshaft. The crankshaft in a reciprocating engine converts the linear motion of the pistons into rotary motion, which drives the wheels or other machinery."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. Which type of fastener is designed to create a temporary joint and can be easily removed without damage?",
      options: ["A. Welding", "B. Rivet", "C. Screw", "D. Adhesive bonding"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Screw. Screws are fasteners that create a temporary joint and can be easily removed without causing damage to the components."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What machine element is used to maintain tension in a chain or belt drive system?",
      options: ["A. Gear", "B. Bearing", "C. Tensioner", "D. Spring"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Tensioner. A tensioner is used to maintain proper tension in a chain or belt drive system, ensuring efficient power transmission."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. Which type of bearing is suitable for supporting axial loads in one direction and requires thrust collars to maintain axial alignment?",
      options: [
        "A. Ball bearing",
        "B. Roller bearing",
        "C. Thrust bearing",
        "D. Tapered bearing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Thrust bearing. Thrust bearings are designed to support axial loads in one direction and may require thrust collars to maintain axial alignment."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is the primary function of a flexible coupling in a rotating machinery system?",
      options: [
        "A. To transmit power",
        "B. To support radial loads",
        "C. To reduce vibrations",
        "D. To change the direction of rotation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. To transmit power. Flexible couplings are used to transmit power between two shafts while accommodating misalignment and reducing vibrations."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which type of gear is known for its ability to transmit high power between parallel shafts and is commonly used in industrial applications?",
      options: [
        "A. Spur gear",
        "B. Helical gear",
        "C. Bevel gear",
        "D. Worm gear"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Helical gear. Helical gears are commonly used to transmit high power between parallel shafts in industrial applications, thanks to their improved load distribution and quiet operation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the purpose of a splined connection in a machine element?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide flexibility",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To prevent relative rotation",
        "D. To reduce vibrations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To transmit power. Splined connections are used to transmit power between shafts with high torque and axial loads."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. Which type of bearing is suitable for applications where heavy radial loads and thrust loads in both directions need to be supported?",
      options: [
        "A. Ball bearing",
        "B. Roller bearing",
        "C. Thrust bearing",
        "D. Tapered bearing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Tapered bearing. Tapered bearings are designed to support heavy radial loads and thrust loads in both directions, making them suitable for such applications."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the primary purpose of a bushing in a machine element?",
      options: [
        "A. To align shafts",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To reduce friction",
        "D. To change direction of rotation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To reduce friction. Bushings are used to reduce friction between moving parts and provide a sliding surface for a shaft."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. In a chain drive system, what is the function of a sprocket?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide radial support",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To reduce vibrations",
        "D. To change the direction of rotation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To transmit power. Sprockets are used in chain drive systems to transmit power from one shaft to another using a roller chain."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. Which type of fastener creates a permanent joint by melting and fusing materials together?",
      options: ["A. Bolt", "B. Nut", "C. Welding", "D. Cotter pin"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Welding. Welding is a process that creates a permanent joint by melting and fusing materials together."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the primary function of a gasket in a machine element?",
      options: [
        "A. To transmit power",
        "B. To create a temporary joint",
        "C. To reduce friction",
        "D. To provide a sealing barrier"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To provide a sealing barrier. Gaskets are used to create a tight and leak-free seal between two components in a machine element."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. Which type of chain drive is known for its ability to transmit heavy loads and is commonly used in industrial applications?",
      options: [
        "A. Roller chain drive",
        "B. V-belt drive",
        "C. Gear drive",
        "D. Flat belt drive"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Roller chain drive. Roller chain drives are known for their ability to transmit heavy loads and are widely used in industrial applications where reliability is crucial."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the primary purpose of a cotter pin in a machine element?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide radial support",
        "B. To transmit power",
        "C. To align shafts",
        "D. To prevent axial movement"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To prevent axial movement. Cotter pins are used to prevent axial movement of components, such as nuts and bolts, by securing them in place."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. Which machine element is used to change the direction of rotation between two shafts that intersect at a slight angle (usually less than 45 degrees)?",
      options: [
        "A. Spur gear",
        "B. Helical gear",
        "C. Bevel gear",
        "D. Worm gear"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Worm gear. Worm gears are used to change the direction of rotation between two shafts that intersect at a slight angle, typically less than 45 degrees."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. In a bearing, what is the primary function of the lubrication system?",
      options: [
        "A. To transmit power",
        "B. To provide radial support",
        "C. To reduce friction",
        "D. To create a sealing barrier"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To reduce friction. The lubrication system in a bearing is responsible for reducing friction and preventing wear and heat generation between moving parts.")
];

List<QuestionModel> machinedesign = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. What is the process of creating a plan or design for a machine, component, or system called?",
      options: ["Manufacturing", "Engineering", "Production", "Operation"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The process of creating a plan or design for a machine, component, or system is called engineering. It involves the application of scientific and mathematical principles to design functional and efficient machines and systems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. Which of the following is a primary consideration in machine design to ensure safety and functionality?",
      options: ["Complexity", "Aesthetics", "Simplicity", "Cost"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Simplicity is a primary consideration in machine design to ensure safety and functionality. Simple designs are often easier to understand, operate, and maintain."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. What is the term for a mechanical component that transmits power from one part of a machine to another?",
      options: ["Frame", "Chassis", "Gear", "Spring"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "A gear is a mechanical component that transmits power from one part of a machine to another. Gears are used for speed reduction, speed increase, and torque transmission in various machines."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. In machine design, what is the term for the allowable deformation or displacement in a component under an applied load?",
      options: ["Stress", "Strain", "Elasticity", "Deflection"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "In machine design, the term for the allowable deformation or displacement in a component under an applied load is deflection. It is important to limit deflection to ensure proper functioning of the machine."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. Which of the following is a factor to consider in material selection for machine design?",
      options: ["Color", "Weight", "Density", "Strength"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Strength is a crucial factor to consider in material selection for machine design. The material used must have sufficient strength to withstand the loads and stresses it will experience in the machine."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What is the term for the study of the behavior of materials under load, including their deformation and failure?",
      options: [
        "Kinematics",
        "Statics",
        "Strength of Materials",
        "Thermodynamics"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The study of the behavior of materials under load, including their deformation and failure, is called Strength of Materials. It is a fundamental aspect of machine design."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. Which of the following is a key consideration in machine design to ensure proper functionality and performance?",
      options: ["Aesthetics", "Complexity", "Safety", "Color"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Safety is a key consideration in machine design to ensure proper functionality and performance. Machines must be designed with safety in mind to prevent accidents and injuries."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. In machine design, what is the term for the measure of a material's ability to resist deformation under an applied load?",
      options: ["Elasticity", "Hardness", "Strength", "Stiffness"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The measure of a material's ability to resist deformation under an applied load is referred to as elasticity. Elastic materials return to their original shape after the load is removed."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is the term for the total path length traveled by an object in a specific direction in machine design?",
      options: ["Speed", "Velocity", "Acceleration", "Displacement"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The total path length traveled by an object in a specific direction in machine design is called displacement. It is a vector quantity that includes both magnitude and direction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. What is the term for the design consideration that involves the arrangement and layout of components within a machine or system?",
      options: [
        "Material selection",
        "Aesthetics",
        "Color choice",
        "Configuration"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The design consideration that involves the arrangement and layout of components within a machine or system is called configuration. It affects the machine's functionality and efficiency."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. Which of the following is a key factor in bearing design to ensure proper operation and longevity?",
      options: ["Color", "Material", "Weight", "Texture"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Material is a key factor in bearing design to ensure proper operation and longevity. The choice of bearing material affects its friction, wear, and load-bearing capabilities."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the term for the design consideration that involves the appearance and visual appeal of a machine or product?",
      options: ["Complexity", "Safety", "Aesthetics", "Strength"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Aesthetics is the design consideration that involves the appearance and visual appeal of a machine or product. It focuses on the product's visual design, colors, and style."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. In machine design, what is the term for the measure of a material's resistance to wear and abrasion?",
      options: ["Elasticity", "Hardness", "Strength", "Stiffness"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Hardness is the measure of a material's resistance to wear and abrasion. It is an important factor in the selection of materials for machine components."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What is the term for the allowable load or force that a component can withstand without failure?",
      options: ["Stress", "Strain", "Elasticity", "Load capacity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The allowable load or force that a component can withstand without failure is called stress. It is a critical consideration in machine design."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. Which of the following is a common material used in machine design for its high strength and corrosion resistance?",
      options: ["Aluminum", "Plastic", "Wood", "Stainless Steel"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Stainless Steel is a common material used in machine design for its high strength and corrosion resistance. It is suitable for various applications."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. In machine design, what is the term for the study of forces and their effects on objects at rest or in motion?",
      options: ["Kinematics", "Statics", "Strength of Materials", "Dynamics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The study of forces and their effects on objects at rest or in motion is called Statics. It is an essential part of machine design analysis."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. Which of the following is a type of gear commonly used to transmit power between parallel shafts?",
      options: ["Spur gear", "Helical gear", "Bevel gear", "Worm gear"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "Spur gear is a type of gear commonly used to transmit power between parallel shafts. It has teeth that are parallel to the shaft's axis."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. In machine design, what is the term for the factor of safety that takes into account variations in material properties and loads?",
      options: [
        "Ultimate strength",
        "Yield strength",
        "Safety factor",
        "Allowable stress"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The factor of safety that takes into account variations in material properties and loads is called the safety factor. It ensures that the design can withstand uncertainties and variations."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. Which of the following is a commonly used method for joining two metal parts together in machine design?",
      options: ["Welding", "Gluing", "Sewing", "Bolting"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "Welding is a commonly used method for joining two metal parts together in machine design. It creates a strong and permanent bond between the parts."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the term for the study of the motion and behavior of objects without considering the forces that cause that motion in machine design?",
      options: ["Dynamics", "Kinematics", "Statics", "Thermodynamics"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The study of the motion and behavior of objects without considering the forces that cause that motion is called Kinematics. It focuses on describing and analyzing motion.")
];

List<QuestionModel> manufacturingprocess = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. Which manufacturing process involves the removal of material from a workpiece using cutting tools?",
      options: ["Casting", "Milling", "Forging", "Welding"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Milling is a manufacturing process that involves the removal of material from a workpiece using cutting tools. It is a versatile process for creating a wide range of shapes and features."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. In metal forming processes, what is the term for the operation that reduces the thickness of a workpiece by compressing it between two rolls?",
      options: ["Drawing", "Extrusion", "Rolling", "Punching"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Rolling is the operation in metal forming processes that reduces the thickness of a workpiece by compressing it between two rolls. It is commonly used in sheet metal production."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. Which of the following is a common additive manufacturing process that uses a laser or electron beam to fuse metal powder together layer by layer?",
      options: ["Injection molding", "Casting", "3D printing", "Machining"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "3D printing is a common additive manufacturing process that uses a laser or electron beam to fuse metal powder together layer by layer, creating complex geometries."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. What is the term for a manufacturing process that involves heating a material to a high temperature and then cooling it quickly to change its properties?",
      options: ["Milling", "Annealing", "Welding", "Forging"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Annealing is a manufacturing process that involves heating a material to a high temperature and then cooling it quickly to change its properties, often to reduce hardness and increase ductility."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. Which manufacturing process involves shaping a workpiece by forcing it through a die orifice to create a desired cross-sectional shape?",
      options: ["Casting", "Extrusion", "Milling", "Machining"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Extrusion is a manufacturing process that involves shaping a workpiece by forcing it through a die orifice to create a desired cross-sectional shape. It is commonly used for producing long profiles."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "6. In the context of welding, what does TIG stand for?",
      options: [
        "Thermal Inert Gas",
        "Tungsten Inert Gas",
        "Titanium Inert Gas",
        "Torch Inert Gas"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "TIG stands for Tungsten Inert Gas welding. It is a welding process that uses a non-consumable tungsten electrode and an inert gas to create a weld."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. Which manufacturing process involves heating a material to a temperature just below its melting point and then applying pressure to join two pieces together?",
      options: ["Sintering", "Brazing", "Forging", "Casting"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Brazing is a manufacturing process that involves heating a material to a temperature just below its melting point and then applying pressure to join two pieces together using a filler material (usually a metal alloy)."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. Which manufacturing process involves heating a workpiece to a high temperature and then cooling it slowly to remove internal stresses and improve its hardness and strength?",
      options: ["Quenching", "Tempering", "Annealing", "Milling"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Annealing is the manufacturing process that involves heating a workpiece to a high temperature and then cooling it slowly to remove internal stresses and improve its hardness and strength."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is the term for the process of converting a solid material directly into a vapor, which is then condensed back into a solid without passing through a liquid phase?",
      options: ["Casting", "Machining", "Sintering", "Sublimation"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Sublimation is the process of converting a solid material directly into a vapor, which is then condensed back into a solid without passing through a liquid phase. It is used in some manufacturing processes."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. In plastic injection molding, what is the term for the cavity in the mold that gives shape to the final plastic part?",
      options: ["Runner", "Gate", "Core", "Cavity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The cavity in the mold that gives shape to the final plastic part in injection molding is called the cavity. It is the negative space of the part to be produced."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "11. What is the primary purpose of a machining process?",
      options: [
        "Joining materials",
        "Heating materials",
        "Removing material",
        "Forming materials"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The primary purpose of a machining process is to remove material from a workpiece to create the desired shape and size."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. Which of the following is a common abrasive machining process that uses a rotating abrasive wheel to remove material from a workpiece?",
      options: ["Casting", "Milling", "Grinding", "Extrusion"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Grinding is a common abrasive machining process that uses a rotating abrasive wheel to remove material from a workpiece, typically for achieving high precision and surface finish."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the term for the manufacturing process that involves creating a part by depositing material layer by layer, often used in 3D printing?",
      options: ["Milling", "Casting", "Additive Manufacturing", "Forging"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Additive Manufacturing is the manufacturing process that involves creating a part by depositing material layer by layer, often used in 3D printing and other additive techniques."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. Which manufacturing process involves shaping a workpiece by compressing it between two dies to create a desired cross-sectional shape?",
      options: ["Extrusion", "Machining", "Casting", "Injection molding"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Injection molding is a manufacturing process that involves shaping a workpiece by compressing it between two dies to create a desired cross-sectional shape. It is commonly used for producing plastic parts."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "15. In the context of metalworking, what does CNC stand for?",
      options: [
        "Computer Numerical Control",
        "Center for New Castings",
        "Cutting and Nibbling Control",
        "Continuous Nanoscale Cutting"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "CNC stands for Computer Numerical Control, which is a technology that automates machine tools for precision and efficiency in manufacturing processes."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. Which manufacturing process involves heating a material to a high temperature and then rapidly cooling it to create a hardened surface layer?",
      options: ["Annealing", "Quenching", "Tempering", "Sintering"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Quenching is the manufacturing process that involves heating a material to a high temperature and then rapidly cooling it to create a hardened surface layer, improving its hardness and strength."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the term for the process of using a mold to create a part by pouring molten material into it and allowing it to solidify?",
      options: ["Sintering", "Brazing", "Casting", "Forging"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Casting is the process of using a mold to create a part by pouring molten material into it and allowing it to solidify. It's a widely used manufacturing method."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. In the context of sheet metal fabrication, what is the term for the process of bending a sheet to create angles and shapes?",
      options: ["Drawing", "Rolling", "Folding", "Punching"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Folding is the process in sheet metal fabrication that involves bending a sheet to create angles and shapes. It's a common technique in the industry."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. Which manufacturing process is commonly used for creating hollow, cylindrical parts by rotating a workpiece on a lathe?",
      options: ["Extrusion", "Milling", "Turning", "Grinding"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Turning is a manufacturing process commonly used for creating hollow, cylindrical parts by rotating a workpiece on a lathe and removing material."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the term for a manufacturing process that involves heating a powder to bond its particles without melting them?",
      options: ["Sintering", "Quenching", "Annealing", "Brazing"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "Sintering is a manufacturing process that involves heating a powder to bond its particles without melting them. It's used for creating solid objects from powdered material.")
];

List<QuestionModel> materialscience = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. What is the term for the ability of a material to resist deformation or failure under applied loads?",
      options: ["Density", "Hardness", "Elasticity", "Thermal conductivity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The ability of a material to resist deformation or failure under applied loads is called elasticity. Elastic materials return to their original shape when the applied load is removed."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. Which of the following is an example of a ductile material?",
      options: ["Glass", "Aluminum", "Ceramic", "Concrete"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Aluminum is an example of a ductile material. Ductile materials can be stretched into wires without breaking."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. What is the term for a material's ability to absorb energy when deformed elastically and release it when unloaded?",
      options: ["Brittleness", "Stress", "Toughness", "Resilience"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The ability of a material to absorb energy when deformed elastically and release it when unloaded is called resilience. It is a measure of a material's ability to withstand shock or impact."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. What property of a material refers to its resistance to scratching, wear, and indentation?",
      options: ["Thermal conductivity", "Density", "Hardness", "Elasticity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Hardness is the property of a material that refers to its resistance to scratching, wear, and indentation. It is often measured on the Mohs scale or using the Rockwell or Vickers hardness tests."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What is the term for the ability of a material to transmit heat?",
      options: [
        "Thermal expansion",
        "Thermal conductivity",
        "Thermal diffusivity",
        "Thermal capacity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The ability of a material to transmit heat is called thermal conductivity. Materials with high thermal conductivity can efficiently conduct heat."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What type of material can return to its original shape after being deformed under a load?",
      options: ["Brittle", "Elastic", "Plastic", "Ductile"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Elastic materials can return to their original shape after being deformed under a load. This property is associated with materials like rubber bands and springs."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the term for the ratio of the load to the original cross-sectional area of a material?",
      options: ["Stress", "Strain", "Modulus of elasticity", "Shear strength"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The ratio of the load to the original cross-sectional area of a material is called stress. It is a measure of the internal resistance to deformation caused by an applied load."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the term for the measure of a material's ability to withstand shear forces without failing?",
      options: ["Stress", "Strain", "Toughness", "Shear strength"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The measure of a material's ability to withstand shear forces without failing is called shear strength. It is particularly important in applications involving shearing and cutting."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. What is the term for the point at which a material fails under an applied load?",
      options: [
        "Yield point",
        "Ultimate strength",
        "Elastic limit",
        "Proportional limit"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The point at which a material fails under an applied load is called the ultimate strength. It is the maximum stress a material can withstand before failure."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which material property describes a material's ability to undergo large plastic deformation without breaking?",
      options: ["Elasticity", "Malleability", "Ductility", "Hardness"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Ductility is the material property that describes a material's ability to undergo large plastic deformation without breaking. Ductile materials can be stretched into wires."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the term for the deformation of a material in response to an applied load?",
      options: ["Stress", "Strain", "Hardness", "Fracture"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The deformation of a material in response to an applied load is called strain. It is a measure of the relative change in shape or size of a material."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the term for the property of a material that describes its ability to absorb energy without breaking or fracturing?",
      options: ["Resilience", "Stiffness", "Plasticity", "Hardness"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The property of a material that describes its ability to absorb energy without breaking or fracturing is called resilience. It is a measure of a material's ability to withstand shock or impact."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the term for the ability of a material to return to its original shape and size after being subjected to a deforming force?",
      options: ["Brittleness", "Stress", "Toughness", "Elasticity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The ability of a material to return to its original shape and size after being subjected to a deforming force is called elasticity. Elastic materials exhibit this property."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What is the term for the tendency of a material to break or shatter without undergoing significant deformation?",
      options: ["Stiffness", "Ductility", "Plasticity", "Brittleness"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The tendency of a material to break or shatter without undergoing significant deformation is called brittleness. Brittle materials do not exhibit plastic deformation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. Which of the following is an example of a ceramic material?",
      options: ["Aluminum", "Steel", "Glass", "Rubber"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "Glass is an example of a ceramic material. Ceramics are typically hard and brittle materials with high-temperature stability."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the term for a material's resistance to permanent deformation under an applied load?",
      options: ["Toughness", "Elasticity", "Plasticity", "Stiffness"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "A material's resistance to permanent deformation under an applied load is referred to as elasticity. Elastic materials return to their original shape after the load is removed."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What property of a material describes its ability to absorb energy up to the point of failure?",
      options: [
        "Yield strength",
        "Toughness",
        "Elastic limit",
        "Ultimate strength"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The property of a material that describes its ability to absorb energy up to the point of failure is called toughness. It is a measure of a material's ability to withstand sudden impact."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the term for the maximum stress that a material can withstand without permanent deformation?",
      options: [
        "Yield strength",
        "Ultimate strength",
        "Elastic limit",
        "Proportional limit"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The maximum stress that a material can withstand without permanent deformation is called yield strength. It is a critical parameter in material testing and design."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the term for the ability of a material to undergo plastic deformation without breaking?",
      options: ["Elasticity", "Malleability", "Brittleness", "Hardness"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Malleability is the ability of a material to undergo plastic deformation without breaking. Malleable materials can be rolled or hammered into thin sheets or shapes."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the term for the measure of a material's stiffness and resistance to elastic deformation?",
      options: ["Elasticity", "Malleability", "Stiffness", "Plasticity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The measure of a material's stiffness and resistance to elastic deformation is called stiffness. It is associated with a material's rigidity.")
];

List<QuestionModel> mechanics = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. Which of the following quantities is a vector?",
      options: ["Speed", "Mass", "Distance", "Velocity"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "Velocity is a vector quantity because it has both magnitude and direction. Speed, mass, and distance are scalar quantities as they only have magnitude."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. According to Newton's second law of motion, the acceleration of an object is directly proportional to the net force acting on it and inversely proportional to its:",
      options: ["Velocity", "Mass", "Distance", "Time"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "According to Newton's second law of motion, the acceleration of an object is directly proportional to the net force acting on it and inversely proportional to its mass. This relationship is described by the formula F = ma, where F is the force, m is the mass, and a is the acceleration."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. When an object moves in a circular path at a constant speed, what is the direction of its acceleration?",
      options: [
        "Towards the center of the circle",
        "Away from the center of the circle",
        "Tangential to the circle",
        "Parallel to the circle"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "When an object moves in a circular path at a constant speed, its acceleration is directed towards the center of the circle. This is called centripetal acceleration and is necessary to keep the object in circular motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. What is the relationship between an object's weight and its mass?",
      options: [
        "Weight is equal to mass",
        "Weight is directly proportional to mass",
        "Weight is inversely proportional to mass",
        "Weight is the product of mass and acceleration due to gravity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The weight of an object is the product of its mass and the acceleration due to gravity. So, weight = mass * acceleration due to gravity. Weight is measured in newtons (N)."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. In the absence of air resistance, if you drop two objects of different masses from the same height, which one will hit the ground first?",
      options: [
        "The heavier object",
        "The lighter object",
        "Both will hit at the same time",
        "It depends on their shapes"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "In the absence of air resistance, both objects will hit the ground at the same time, regardless of their masses. This is a demonstration of the equivalence principle."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. What is the name of the force that opposes the relative motion or tendency of such motion between two surfaces in contact?",
      options: [
        "Centripetal force",
        "Gravitational force",
        "Frictional force",
        "Tension force"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The force that opposes the relative motion or tendency of such motion between two surfaces in contact is called frictional force. It is responsible for creating resistance to motion and is present in various forms, such as static and kinetic friction."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the principle that states an object at rest will remain at rest, and an object in motion will remain in motion with the same speed and in the same direction unless acted upon by an unbalanced external force?",
      options: [
        "Newton's first law of motion",
        "Newton's second law of motion",
        "Newton's third law of motion",
        "Principle of conservation of energy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The principle that states an object at rest will remain at rest, and an object in motion will remain in motion with the same speed and in the same direction unless acted upon by an unbalanced external force is Newton's first law of motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the measure of an object's resistance to changes in its rotational motion?",
      options: ["Inertia", "Momentum", "Force", "Acceleration"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The measure of an object's resistance to changes in its rotational motion is called inertia. It is similar to mass in linear motion and depends on the distribution of mass in the object."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. When an object is in equilibrium, the sum of the forces acting on it is:",
      options: [
        "Zero",
        "Equal to its mass",
        "In the same direction",
        "Opposite to its velocity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "When an object is in equilibrium, the sum of the forces acting on it is zero. This means that the net force is balanced, and the object is not accelerating."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which of the following statements about work and energy is true?",
      options: [
        "Work is a form of energy.",
        "Energy is a form of work.",
        "Work and energy are unrelated concepts.",
        "Work is a measure of an object's mass."
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "Work is a form of energy. Work is the transfer of energy from one system to another, and energy can exist in various forms, including kinetic energy, potential energy, and thermal energy."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the unit of force in the International System of Units (SI)?",
      options: ["Watt", "Newton", "Joule", "Pascal"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The unit of force in the International System of Units (SI) is the newton (N). One newton is the force required to accelerate a one-kilogram mass at a rate of one meter per second squared."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. In the context of mechanical advantage, what is the purpose of a simple machine like a lever or pulley?",
      options: [
        "To decrease the input force required to do work",
        "To increase the input force required to do work",
        "To decrease the work output",
        "To increase the work output"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The purpose of a simple machine like a lever or pulley is to decrease the input force required to do work. Simple machines allow us to achieve mechanical advantage by trading force for distance."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. According to Hooke's law, what is the relationship between the force applied to a spring and the resulting deformation of the spring?",
      options: [
        "Force is directly proportional to deformation.",
        "Force is inversely proportional to deformation.",
        "Force is unrelated to deformation.",
        "Force is equal to deformation."
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "According to Hooke's law, the force applied to a spring is directly proportional to the deformation or change in length of the spring. Mathematically, F = -kx, where F is the force, k is the spring constant, and x is the deformation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What is the term for the force that opposes the motion of an object through a fluid (liquid or gas)?",
      options: [
        "Frictional force",
        "Tension force",
        "Drag force",
        "Centripetal force"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The force that opposes the motion of an object through a fluid is called drag force. It is responsible for slowing down objects moving through air or water."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. According to the law of conservation of momentum, in the absence of external forces, the total momentum of a closed system:",
      options: [
        "Decreases",
        "Increases",
        "Remains constant",
        "Reverses direction"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "According to the law of conservation of momentum, in the absence of external forces, the total momentum of a closed system remains constant. This law applies to both linear and angular momentum."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. When an object is in free fall near the surface of the Earth, what is the acceleration due to gravity (ignoring air resistance)?",
      options: ["1 m/s²", "10 m/s²", "50 m/s²", "100 m/s²"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "Near the surface of the Earth, the acceleration due to gravity is approximately 10 m/s². This value is often rounded to 9.81 m/s² for calculations."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. What is the term for the point at which an object's weight appears to act, causing no rotation or moment about that point?",
      options: ["Center of mass", "Center of gravity", "Fulcrum", "Lever arm"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The point at which an object's weight appears to act, causing no rotation or moment about that point, is called the center of gravity. It is often used in equilibrium and balance calculations."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What type of motion is exhibited by an object in free fall when the only force acting on it is gravity?",
      options: [
        "Uniform motion",
        "Uniform circular motion",
        "Rectilinear motion",
        "Projectile motion"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "An object in free fall, when the only force acting on it is gravity, exhibits rectilinear motion. It moves in a straight line with constant acceleration due to gravity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the term for the rate of change of velocity of an object with respect to time?",
      options: ["Displacement", "Speed", "Acceleration", "Force"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The rate of change of velocity of an object with respect to time is called acceleration. Acceleration can involve an increase or decrease in speed, a change in direction, or both."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What principle states that for every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction?",
      options: [
        "Newton's first law of motion",
        "Newton's second law of motion",
        "Newton's third law of motion",
        "Law of conservation of momentum"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The principle that states for every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction is Newton's third law of motion. This law describes how forces interact between objects.")
];

List<QuestionModel> mechatronics = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. What is Mechatronics?",
      options: [
        "A. A branch of mechanical engineering",
        "B. A combination of mechanics and electronics",
        "C. A type of computer programming",
        "D. A form of biological engineering"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Mechatronics is a multidisciplinary field that combines mechanical engineering and electronics. It involves integrating mechanical systems with electronics, control systems, and computer technology to create intelligent and automated systems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. Which component of a mechatronic system is responsible for making decisions and controlling the overall operation?",
      options: [
        "A. Actuator",
        "B. Sensor",
        "C. Microcontroller",
        "D. Power supply"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Microcontroller. The microcontroller is the component that makes decisions and controls the overall operation of a mechatronic system. It processes data from sensors and sends commands to actuators to achieve desired tasks."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. What is the primary purpose of sensors in a mechatronic system?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide power to the system",
        "B. To process data and make decisions",
        "C. To detect and measure physical quantities",
        "D. To provide mechanical motion"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To detect and measure physical quantities. Sensors in a mechatronic system are used to detect and measure various physical parameters such as temperature, pressure, distance, and more. This data is then used for control and decision-making."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which of the following is an example of a common application of mechatronics in everyday life?",
      options: [
        "A. Microwave ovens",
        "B. Telecommunications networks",
        "C. Artificial intelligence research",
        "D. Archaeological excavations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Microwave ovens. Mechatronics is commonly applied in household appliances like microwave ovens, where it combines mechanical components, sensors, and control systems to cook food efficiently and safely."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "5. In mechatronics, what are actuators responsible for?",
      options: [
        "A. Measuring physical quantities",
        "B. Making decisions and control",
        "C. Providing power to the system",
        "D. Generating mechanical motion"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Generating mechanical motion. Actuators in mechatronics are devices that convert electrical signals into mechanical motion. They are responsible for physically moving or manipulating objects in a mechatronic system."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "6. What does PID control stand for in mechatronics?",
      options: [
        "A. Proportional-Integral-Derivative control",
        "B. Power Input Distribution control",
        "C. Precision-Instrument Display control",
        "D. Positional Improvement Device control"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Proportional-Integral-Derivative control (PID control). PID control is a common control mechanism in mechatronics that uses three terms (proportional, integral, and derivative) to control and regulate systems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. Which type of sensors are commonly used to detect the presence or absence of objects in mechatronic systems?",
      options: [
        "A. Thermocouples",
        "B. Infrared sensors",
        "C. Load cells",
        "D. Accelerometers"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Infrared sensors. Infrared sensors are often used for object detection in mechatronic systems. They emit and detect infrared radiation, making them suitable for detecting the presence or absence of objects."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the purpose of a Haptic feedback system in mechatronics?",
      options: [
        "A. To display visual information",
        "B. To provide tactile feedback to the user",
        "C. To store data",
        "D. To improve wireless communication"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. To provide tactile feedback to the user. Haptic feedback systems in mechatronics are designed to provide tactile sensations to the user, allowing them to feel and interact with virtual or remote environments."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "9. In mechatronics, what does the term 'closed-loop control' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. Control system without sensors",
        "B. Control system without actuators",
        "C. Control system with feedback",
        "D. Control system with no microcontroller"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Control system with feedback. Closed-loop control in mechatronics refers to a control system that uses feedback from sensors to continuously adjust and improve the system's performance."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which mechatronic system component is responsible for converting electrical energy into another form of energy (e.g., mechanical motion or heat)?",
      options: [
        "A. Sensor",
        "B. Actuator",
        "C. Microcontroller",
        "D. Power supply"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Actuator. Actuators in mechatronics are responsible for converting electrical energy into another form of energy, typically mechanical motion. This enables them to perform various tasks and functions."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. What is the role of a power supply in a mechatronic system?",
      options: [
        "A. To measure physical quantities",
        "B. To provide mechanical motion",
        "C. To generate decisions and control",
        "D. To provide electrical energy to the system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. To provide electrical energy to the system. The power supply in a mechatronic system is responsible for providing the electrical energy needed to operate the various components, including sensors, actuators, and microcontrollers."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. Which programming language is commonly used for controlling and programming mechatronic systems?",
      options: ["A. Python", "B. Java", "C. C++", "D. HTML"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. C++. C++ is a commonly used programming language for controlling and programming mechatronic systems due to its efficiency and real-time capabilities."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the primary purpose of feedback control in mechatronics?",
      options: [
        "A. To prevent sensor malfunction",
        "B. To eliminate the need for actuators",
        "C. To adjust system behavior based on sensor data",
        "D. To increase power supply voltage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To adjust system behavior based on sensor data. Feedback control in mechatronics uses sensor data to continuously adjust and regulate the system's behavior, ensuring it operates as intended."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What is the key advantage of mechatronic systems in industrial automation?",
      options: [
        "A. They require less power",
        "B. They are less expensive",
        "C. They improve efficiency and flexibility",
        "D. They are easier to manufacture"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. They improve efficiency and flexibility. Mechatronic systems in industrial automation offer the advantage of improved efficiency and flexibility in manufacturing and production processes, allowing for automation and adaptation to various tasks."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What does the term 'Real-time control' mean in mechatronics?",
      options: [
        "A. Control without any delay",
        "B. Control in virtual environments",
        "C. Control based on user interaction",
        "D. Control in slow motion"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Control without any delay. Real-time control in mechatronics means that control actions are executed without any significant delay, ensuring that the system can respond to changes quickly and accurately."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. Which component of a mechatronic system is responsible for detecting and responding to changes in the system's environment?",
      options: [
        "A. Actuator",
        "B. Sensor",
        "C. Microcontroller",
        "D. Power supply"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Sensor. Sensors in a mechatronic system are designed to detect changes in the system's environment, such as temperature, pressure, or the presence of objects, and provide data for control and decision-making."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. In mechatronics, what is the term for a pre-programmed sequence of actions or operations that a system follows?",
      options: [
        "A. Feedback loop",
        "B. Algorithm",
        "C. Actuation process",
        "D. Data logging"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Algorithm. In mechatronics, an algorithm is a pre-programmed sequence of actions or operations that a system follows to achieve a specific task or function."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the primary function of a control system in mechatronics?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide power to the system",
        "B. To generate mechanical motion",
        "C. To regulate and coordinate system behavior",
        "D. To measure physical quantities"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To regulate and coordinate system behavior. Control systems in mechatronics are responsible for regulating and coordinating the behavior of the system's components, ensuring they work together harmoniously to achieve the desired objectives."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. Which of the following industries commonly uses mechatronics in the design and production of products?",
      options: ["A. Agriculture", "B. Banking", "C. Fashion", "D. Tourism"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Agriculture. Mechatronics is commonly used in agriculture for various purposes, including automated farming equipment, precision agriculture, and crop monitoring systems."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. In mechatronics, what does the term 'multi-domain' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. Control of multiple systems at once",
        "B. Use of multiple programming languages",
        "C. Integration of multiple engineering disciplines",
        "D. Operation in multiple physical locations"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Integration of multiple engineering disciplines. In mechatronics, 'multi-domain' refers to the integration of multiple engineering disciplines, such as mechanical, electrical, and software engineering, to design and control complex systems.")
];

List<QuestionModel> solidmechanics = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. What is the primary focus of Solid Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. The study of fluid dynamics",
        "B. The behavior of solids under various loads",
        "C. The study of thermodynamics",
        "D. The analysis of electrical circuits"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. The behavior of solids under various loads. Solid Mechanics is a branch of mechanics that focuses on the study of the behavior of solid materials, including how they respond to different loads and deformations."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "2. Which of the following materials is typically considered an isotropic material in Solid Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. Wood",
        "B. Rubber",
        "C. Steel",
        "D. Fiber-reinforced composite"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Steel. Isotropic materials have uniform mechanical properties in all directions. Steel is often considered isotropic because its properties are relatively consistent regardless of the direction of loading."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. What is the term for the ability of a material to return to its original shape after deformation when the load is removed?",
      options: [
        "A. Elasticity",
        "B. Plasticity",
        "C. Ductility",
        "D. Hardness"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Elasticity. Elasticity is the property of a material to return to its original shape when the applied load is removed. It is a key characteristic of elastic materials."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which principle in Solid Mechanics states that the internal stresses within a material are proportional to the applied load or deformation?",
      options: [
        "A. Hooke's Law",
        "B. Newton's Law",
        "C. Pascal's Law",
        "D. Archimedes' Principle"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Hooke's Law. Hooke's Law is a fundamental principle in Solid Mechanics that states that the internal stresses within a material are directly proportional to the applied load or deformation, provided the material remains within its elastic limit."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What is the term for the maximum stress that a material can withstand without permanent deformation?",
      options: [
        "A. Yield stress",
        "B. Ultimate stress",
        "C. Shear stress",
        "D. Tensile stress"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Yield stress. Yield stress is the maximum stress that a material can withstand without undergoing permanent deformation. It marks the transition from elastic to plastic behavior."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "6. In Solid Mechanics, what does the term 'strain' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. A measure of a material's density",
        "B. The internal resistance of a material",
        "C. The ratio of deformation to the original dimension",
        "D. The ability of a material to return to its original shape"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. The ratio of deformation to the original dimension. Strain in Solid Mechanics is a measure of the deformation experienced by a material relative to its original dimension."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. Which of the following is an example of a tension force in Solid Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. Pushing a box on a flat surface",
        "B. A stretching force applied to a cable",
        "C. Twisting a rod",
        "D. Compressing a spring"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. A stretching force applied to a cable. Tension forces in Solid Mechanics are associated with stretching or elongating a material. When you pull on a cable or rope, you apply a tension force."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. What is the term for the deformation of a material when it is subjected to a shear force?",
      options: ["A. Torsion", "B. Compression", "C. Tension", "D. Bending"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Torsion. Torsion is the deformation of a material when it is subjected to a shear force. It results in a twisting or shearing motion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "9. What is the primary function of beams in Solid Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. To measure temperature",
        "B. To store energy",
        "C. To support loads and resist bending",
        "D. To generate electricity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To support loads and resist bending. Beams in Solid Mechanics are structural elements designed to support loads and distribute them while resisting bending and deformation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which Solid Mechanics concept describes the tendency of a material to return to its original shape after deformation?",
      options: [
        "A. Ductility",
        "B. Hardness",
        "C. Elasticity",
        "D. Plasticity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Elasticity. Elasticity is the property that describes a material's ability to return to its original shape after deformation, provided it operates within its elastic limit."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "11. In Solid Mechanics, what is the primary objective of stress analysis?",
      options: [
        "A. To determine the material's color",
        "B. To evaluate the deformation of a material",
        "C. To analyze the internal distribution of forces within a material",
        "D. To measure the density of the material"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To analyze the internal distribution of forces within a material. Stress analysis in Solid Mechanics aims to determine how forces and stresses are distributed within a material, helping to assess its structural integrity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the term for the point at which a material undergoes a sudden and significant reduction in its ability to withstand stress without breaking?",
      options: [
        "A. Elastic limit",
        "B. Yield point",
        "C. Ultimate strength",
        "D. Resilience threshold"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Yield point. The yield point is the point at which a material undergoes a significant reduction in its ability to withstand stress without breaking or experiencing permanent deformation."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. In Solid Mechanics, what is the term for a force that tends to compress or shorten a material?",
      options: [
        "A. Tension force",
        "B. Shear force",
        "C. Bending force",
        "D. Compressive force"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is D. Compressive force. A compressive force is a force that tends to compress or shorten a material, leading to deformation in the direction of the applied force."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. What does the term 'Poisson's ratio' represent in Solid Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. The ratio of tensile stress to tensile strain",
        "B. The ratio of shear stress to shear strain",
        "C. The ratio of lateral strain to axial strain",
        "D. The ratio of elastic modulus to plastic modulus"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. The ratio of lateral strain to axial strain. Poisson's ratio is a material property that represents the ratio of the lateral strain (perpendicular to the applied force) to the axial strain (along the applied force)."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What is the primary purpose of a stress-strain curve in Solid Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. To calculate temperature changes in materials",
        "B. To determine a material's color under stress",
        "C. To understand the relationship between applied stress and resulting strain",
        "D. To measure a material's density"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To understand the relationship between applied stress and resulting strain. A stress-strain curve in Solid Mechanics is used to illustrate how a material responds to applied stress and how it undergoes deformation, providing valuable information about its mechanical properties."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the term for the resistance of a material to permanent deformation or failure under an applied load?",
      options: [
        "A. Elasticity",
        "B. Ductility",
        "C. Plasticity",
        "D. Hardness"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is A. Elasticity. Elasticity refers to a material's ability to resist permanent deformation or failure under an applied load, returning to its original shape when the load is removed."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. Which type of stress in Solid Mechanics results from forces applied perpendicular to the surface of a material?",
      options: [
        "A. Tensile stress",
        "B. Shear stress",
        "C. Compressive stress",
        "D. Torsional stress"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Compressive stress. Compressive stress results from forces applied perpendicular to the surface of a material, leading to compression or shortening."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the term for a measure of a material's ability to absorb energy without fracturing or breaking?",
      options: [
        "A. Elastic limit",
        "B. Ductility",
        "C. Toughness",
        "D. Resilience"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. Toughness. Toughness is a measure of a material's ability to absorb energy without fracturing or breaking. It reflects its capacity to withstand dynamic loads."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the primary objective of a stress analysis in Solid Mechanics?",
      options: [
        "A. To calculate the temperature of a material",
        "B. To evaluate the density of a material",
        "C. To determine how forces and stresses are distributed within a material",
        "D. To assess the color of a material under stress"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is C. To determine how forces and stresses are distributed within a material. Stress analysis in Solid Mechanics aims to assess how forces and stresses are distributed within a material, helping to ensure its structural integrity."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. In Solid Mechanics, what is the term for the ability of a material to withstand loads without experiencing significant deformation or failure?",
      options: [
        "A. Plasticity",
        "B. Elasticity",
        "C. Ductility",
        "D. Hardness"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The correct answer is B. Elasticity. Elasticity is the ability of a material to withstand loads without experiencing significant deformation or failure, returning to its original shape when the load is removed.")
];

List<QuestionModel> thermodynamics = [
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "1. Which of the following laws states that energy cannot be created or destroyed, only transferred or converted from one form to another?",
      options: [
        "First Law of Thermodynamics",
        "Second Law of Thermodynamics",
        "Third Law of Thermodynamics",
        "Zeroth Law of Thermodynamics"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The First Law of Thermodynamics, also known as the law of energy conservation, states that energy cannot be created or destroyed. It can only be transferred or converted from one form to another."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "2. What is the specific heat capacity of a substance?",
      options: [
        "The amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of 1 gram of the substance by 1 degree Celsius.",
        "The amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of 1 kilogram of the substance by 1 degree Celsius.",
        "The temperature at which the substance boils.",
        "The temperature at which the substance freezes."
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The specific heat capacity of a substance is the amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of 1 gram of the substance by 1 degree Celsius. It is a measure of the substance's ability to store thermal energy."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "3. In a thermodynamic process, if the internal energy of a system increases and heat is added to the system, what can be said about the work done by the system?",
      options: [
        "The work done is positive.",
        "The work done is negative.",
        "The work done is zero.",
        "The work done depends on the specific heat of the substance."
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "If the internal energy of a system increases and heat is added to the system, the work done by the system is positive. This is based on the First Law of Thermodynamics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "4. Which law of thermodynamics states that heat flows from hot to cold objects and not the other way around?",
      options: [
        "First Law of Thermodynamics",
        "Second Law of Thermodynamics",
        "Third Law of Thermodynamics",
        "Zeroth Law of Thermodynamics"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The Second Law of Thermodynamics states that heat flows from hot to cold objects and not the other way around. It describes the direction of heat transfer and the irreversibility of certain processes."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "5. What is the absolute temperature scale where zero Kelvin (0 K) represents absolute zero, the lowest possible temperature?",
      options: [
        "Celsius scale",
        "Fahrenheit scale",
        "Rankine scale",
        "Kelvin scale"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "The absolute temperature scale where zero Kelvin (0 K) represents absolute zero is the Kelvin scale. It is the SI unit of temperature measurement."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "6. Which thermodynamic process occurs when a gas expands and cools without the addition or removal of heat?",
      options: [
        "Isothermal process",
        "Adiabatic process",
        "Isobaric process",
        "Isochoric process"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "An adiabatic process occurs when a gas expands and cools without the addition or removal of heat. In such a process, the internal energy of the gas changes due to the work done."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "7. What is the efficiency of a heat engine that takes in 500 J of heat and performs 200 J of work?",
      options: ["40%", "60%", "25%", "80%"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The efficiency of a heat engine is given by the ratio of the work done to the heat input. Efficiency = (Work done / Heat input) * 100%. In this case, Efficiency = (200 J / 500 J) * 100% = 40%."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "8. According to the Third Law of Thermodynamics, as the temperature of a system approaches absolute zero, the entropy of the system approaches:",
      options: [
        "Zero",
        "Infinity",
        "A constant value",
        "Depends on the substance"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "According to the Third Law of Thermodynamics, as the temperature of a system approaches absolute zero, the entropy of the system approaches zero. This law is related to the behavior of matter at extremely low temperatures."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "9. What is the specific heat capacity of water?",
      options: ["1 J/g°C", "4.18 J/g°C", "2.22 J/g°C", "5.00 J/g°C"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The specific heat capacity of water is approximately 4.18 J/g°C. It is relatively high compared to many other substances, which makes water an excellent heat reservoir."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "10. Which thermodynamic process occurs when a gas expands and maintains constant pressure?",
      options: [
        "Isothermal process",
        "Adiabatic process",
        "Isobaric process",
        "Isochoric process"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "An isobaric process occurs when a gas expands and maintains constant pressure. In this process, the volume of the gas changes, but the pressure remains constant."),
  QuestionModel(
      question: "11. What is the heat capacity of an object?",
      options: [
        "The amount of heat needed to raise its temperature by 1 degree Celsius.",
        "The temperature at which it melts.",
        "The temperature at which it boils.",
        "The amount of work it can do."
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The heat capacity of an object is the amount of heat needed to raise its temperature by 1 degree Celsius. It is a measure of the object's ability to absorb heat."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "12. What is the term for the maximum amount of work that can be obtained from a heat engine operating between two reservoirs at different temperatures?",
      options: [
        "Carnot efficiency",
        "Entropy",
        "Adiabatic process",
        "Internal energy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The term for the maximum amount of work that can be obtained from a heat engine operating between two reservoirs at different temperatures is known as the Carnot efficiency. It represents the ideal limit of efficiency for a heat engine."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "13. What is the heat transfer process that occurs through the emission and absorption of electromagnetic waves, such as infrared radiation?",
      options: ["Conduction", "Convection", "Radiation", "Advection"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The heat transfer process that occurs through the emission and absorption of electromagnetic waves, such as infrared radiation, is called radiation. It can occur in a vacuum and does not require a medium."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "14. When a gas undergoes an adiabatic expansion, which of the following properties remains constant?",
      options: ["Temperature", "Pressure", "Volume", "Entropy"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "When a gas undergoes an adiabatic expansion, the entropy remains constant. An adiabatic process is characterized by the absence of heat transfer, which means there is no change in entropy."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "15. What is the term for the point at which a substance changes from a gas to a liquid, or vice versa, at a constant temperature and pressure?",
      options: [
        "Melting point",
        "Boiling point",
        "Triple point",
        "Critical point"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "The term for the point at which a substance changes from a gas to a liquid, or vice versa, at a constant temperature and pressure is the boiling point. It is a characteristic property of the substance."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "16. What is the term for a process in which a system exchanges both heat and work with its surroundings?",
      options: [
        "Adiabatic process",
        "Isothermal process",
        "Isobaric process",
        "Open system process"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution:
          "An isothermal process is a process in which a system exchanges both heat and work with its surroundings while maintaining a constant temperature. It is often used as an idealized process in thermodynamics."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "17. According to the Zeroth Law of Thermodynamics, if two systems are each in thermal equilibrium with a third system, then they are in thermal equilibrium with each other. This law establishes the concept of:",
      options: ["Temperature", "Pressure", "Entropy", "Work"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "According to the Zeroth Law of Thermodynamics, if two systems are each in thermal equilibrium with a third system, then they are in thermal equilibrium with each other. This law establishes the concept of temperature and the basis for temperature measurement."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "18. What is the term for the heat energy required to change a substance from a solid to a liquid at its melting point?",
      options: [
        "Latent heat of fusion",
        "Latent heat of vaporization",
        "Specific heat capacity",
        "Heat capacity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution:
          "The term for the heat energy required to change a substance from a solid to a liquid at its melting point is the latent heat of fusion. It is also known as the heat of fusion."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "19. What is the term for a thermodynamic process that occurs at a constant volume?",
      options: [
        "Isothermal process",
        "Adiabatic process",
        "Isobaric process",
        "Isochoric process"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution:
          "An isochoric process occurs at a constant volume. During such a process, the volume of the system remains constant, and work is usually not done."),
  QuestionModel(
      question:
          "20. What is the term for the measure of disorder or randomness in a system, often associated with the Second Law of Thermodynamics?",
      options: ["Temperature", "Pressure", "Entropy", "Enthalpy"],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution:
          "The term for the measure of disorder or randomness in a system is entropy. It is a fundamental concept in the Second Law of Thermodynamics and is used to describe the direction of spontaneous processes.")
];
